<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<xliff version="1.0">
  <file original="global" source-language="en" datatype="plaintext">
    <body>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje - Intro - eTapasvi.com</source>
        <target>Палден Дордже - Вступление - eTapasvi.com</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Prophecies</source>
        <target>Предсказания</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Ram Bahadur Bomjan, known as</source>
        <target>Рам Бахадур Бомджан, также известный как</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje</source>
        <target>Палден Дордже</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>(his monastic name) was born on</source>
        <target>(его монашеское имя), был рождён 9 апреля 1990 в</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>full moon</source>
        <target>полнолуние</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>April 9,</source>
        <target>в 150</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>1990 in 150 kilometers from Lumbini, the Ratanpuri village, Nepal</source>
        <target>километрах от Лумбини, деревня Ратанпури, Непал</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>His parents are farmers. His mother,</source>
        <target>Его родители фермеры. Его мать,</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Maya Devi</source>
        <target>Майя Деви</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>was married at 12. Amazingly during delivery when only baby's head was just out of the womb, he let out a cry, that echoed in village.</source>
        <target>вышла замуж в 12 лет. Удивительным образом при рождении, как только голова младенца показалась из утробы матери, он издал крик, который был слышен по всей деревне.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He started his meditation on May 16, 2005.</source>
        <target>Он начал свою медитацию 16 мая 2005 года.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>After 7 months Ram was bitten by a snake and monks covered him with curtain. After five days it was opened and Ram spoke:</source>
        <target>Через 7 месяцев Рама укусила змея, и монахи укутали его простыней. Пять дней спустя ткань была сброшена, и Рам заговорил:</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>«...A snake bit me but I do not need treatment. I need 6 years of deep meditation.»</source>
        <target>«...Меня укусила змея, но лечение мне не нужно. Что меня вылечит – это 6 лет медитации».</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>During 9 months he was motionless meditating near the Buddhist’s sacred tree without any food or water.</source>
        <target>9 месяцев он провел неподвижно в медитации без еды и воды рядом со священным для буддистов деревом.</target>
      </trans-unit>     
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On January 19, 2006 he spontaneously</source>
        <target>18 Января 2006 он спонтанно</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje in fire</source>
        <target>Мальчик Будда в огне</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>combusted</source>
        <target>воспламенился</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>, burning off the clothes he has worn for nine months but leaving no scars. After some time in a very soft voice he called for his brother. He asked for a red robe to be thrown over him, he wrapped this close over his body, and he said, let him concentrate on his meditation and do not disturb him.</source>
        <target> на глазах у 59 свидетелей. На нем сгорела одежда, которую он носил в течение девяти месяцев, но не осталось никаких ожогов или шрамов на теле. Через некоторое время очень мягким голосом он позвал своего брата и попросил положить красное одеяние перед ним, чтобы он обернулся в него, и попросил позволить ему сконцентрироваться на медитации и не беспокоить его.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>There is stories of miracles: a girl and a young man had gained the</source>
        <target>Известно о случаях свершения чудес:</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>miracle</source>
        <target>чудо</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>power of speech</source>
        <target>немой девушке</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>although they could not speak...</source>
        <target>и молодому человеку вернулся дар речи...</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Read More about Buddha Boy</source>
        <target>Читать далее про Мальчика Будду</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Read more...</source>
        <target>Читать далее...</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Gautama Buddha</source>
        <target>Гаутама Будда</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Siddhattha Gautama was born in 563 BCE in Lumbini (modern day Nepal). His mother was Maya Devi but she died in seven days after his delivery.</source>
        <target>Сиддхаттха Гаутама родился в Лумбини (современный Непал) в 563 до н. э. Матерью Гаутамы была Майя Деви, но она умерла через семь дней после его рождения.</target>
      </trans-unit>          
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>At the age of 29 he left his home and family to become a monk. Then, sitting under a tree he vowed never to arise until he had found the Truth.</source>
        <target>В возрасте 29 лет оставил свой дом, семью и имущество, чтобы стать монахом. Сев под деревом, он поклялся не вставать, пока не обнаружит Истину.</target>
      </trans-unit>    
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>At the age of 35 in the fifth lunar month he attaining enlightenment. Gautama, from then on, was known as the Buddha or "Awakened One." Buddha is also sometimes translated as "The Enlightened One."</source>
        <target>В 35 лет он достиг «Пробуждения» в майское полнолуние. Тогда его стали называть Гаутама Будда или просто «Будда», что означает «Пробудившийся».</target>
      </trans-unit>     

    </body>
  </file>
</xliff>