<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<xliff version="1.0">
  <file original="global" source-language="en" datatype="plaintext">
    <body>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Buddha Boy - Intro - eTapasvi.com</source>
        <target>Chłopiec Budda - Wstęp - eTapasvi.com</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Prophecies</source>
        <target>Przepowiednie</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Ram Bahadur Bomjan, known as</source>
        <target>Ram Bahadur Bomjan, znany jako</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje</source>
        <target>Palden Dorje</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>(his monastic name) was born on</source>
        <target>(jego imię zakonne) urodził się podczas</target>
      </trans-unit> 
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>full moon</source>
        <target>pełni Księżyca</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>April 9,</source>
        <target>9 kwietnia</target>
      </trans-unit>  
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>1990 in 150 kilometers from Lumbini, the Ratanpuri village, Nepal</source>
        <target>1990 roku, 150 kilometrów od Lumbini, w wiosce Ratanpuri w Nepalu.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>His parents are farmers. His mother,</source>
        <target>Jego rodzice są rolnikami. Jego matka,</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Maya Devi</source>
        <target>Maya Devi,</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>was married at 12. Amazingly during delivery when only baby's head was just out of the womb, he let out a cry, that echoed in village.</source>
        <target>wyszła za mąż mając 12 lat. Zdumiewające jest to, że podczas porodu, kiedy tylko główka noworodka ledwo wyszła z łona, wydał z siebie krzyk, który odbił się echem w wiosce.</target>
      </trans-unit> 
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He started his meditation on May 16, 2005.</source>
        <target>Rozpoczął swą medytację 16 maja 2005 roku.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>After 7 months Ram was bitten by a snake and monks covered him with curtain. After five days it was opened and Ram spoke:</source>
        <target>Po 7 miesiącach Ram został ukąszony przez węża i mnisi zakryli go zasłoną. Po pięciu dniach została odsłonięta, a Ram przemówił:</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>«...A snake bit me but I do not need treatment. I need 6 years of deep meditation.»</source>
        <target>«...Ukąsił mnie wąż, ale nie potrzebuję leczenia. Potrzebuję 6 lat głębokiej medytacji.»</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>During 9 months he was motionless meditating near the Buddhist’s sacred tree without any food or water.</source>
        <target>Podczas 9 miesięcy pozostawał bez ruchu medytując niedaleko świętego drzewa buddyjskiego bez jedzenia i picia.</target>
      </trans-unit>     
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On January 19, 2006 he spontaneously</source>
        <target>18 stycznia, 2006 roku spontanicznie(samoistnie)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje in fire</source>
        <target>Palden Dorje w ogniu</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>combusted</source>
        <target>zapalił się</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>, burning off the clothes he has worn for nine months but leaving no scars. After some time in a very soft voice he called for his brother. He asked for a red robe to be thrown over him, he wrapped this close over his body, and he said, let him concentrate on his meditation and do not disturb him.</source>
        <target>na oczach 59 świadków. Spaliło się na nim ubranie, które nosił od dziewięciu miesięcy, ale nie pozostawiło to na nim żadnych ran. Po pewnym czasie, bardzo cichym głosem wezwał swego brata. Poprosił, by narzucić na niego czerwoną szatę, którą się owinął i poprosił, by pozwolono mu skoncentrować się na jego medytacji i mu nie przeszkadzano.</target>
      </trans-unit>   
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>There are stories of miracles: a girl and a young man had gained the</source>
        <target>Mówi się o wystąpieniu cudów: dziewczynka i młody mężczyzna zyskali</target>
      </trans-unit> 
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>miracle</source>
        <target>cud</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>power of speech</source>
        <target>mowę</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>although they could not speak...</source>
        <target>chociaż przedtem nie mogli mówić</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Read More about Buddha Boy</source>
        <target>Przeczytaj więcej o Chłopcu Buddzie</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Read more...</source>
        <target>Czytaj więcej...</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Gautama Buddha</source>
        <target>Gautama Budda</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Siddhattha Gautama was born in 563 BCE in Lumbini (modern day Nepal). His mother was Maya Devi but she died in seven days after his delivery.</source>
        <target>Siddhartha Gautama urodził się w 563 p.n.e. w Lumbini (dzisiejszy Nepal). Jego matką była Maya Devi, ale zmarła ona siedem dni po porodzie.</target>
      </trans-unit>          
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>At the age of 29 he left his home and family to become a monk. Then, sitting under a tree he vowed never to arise until he had found the Truth.</source>
        <target>W wieku 29 lat opuścił swój dom i rodzinę, by zostać mnichem. Następnie, siedząc pod drzewem przysiągł, że nigdy nie powstanie dopóki nie znajdzie Prawdy.</target>. 
      </trans-unit>    
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>At the age of 35 in the fifth lunar month he attaining enlightenment. Gautama, from then on, was known as the Buddha or "Awakened One." Buddha is also sometimes translated as "The Enlightened One."</source>
        <target>W wieku 35 lat w piątym miesiącu księżycowym doznał oświecenia. Od tego czasu Gautama znany był jako Budda lub "Przebudzony". Budda jest też często tłumaczony jako "Oświecony".</target>
      </trans-unit>     

    </body>
  </file>
</xliff>