<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<xliff version="1.0">
  <file original="global" source-language="en" datatype="plaintext">
    <body>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje - Intro - eTapasvi.com</source>
        <target>Palden Dordže - Úvod - eTapasvi.com</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Prophecies</source>
        <target>Proroctví</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Ram Bahadur Bomjan, known as</source>
        <target>Ram Bahadur Bomdžon, známý pod jménem</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje</source>
        <target>Palden Dordže</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>(his monastic name) was born on</source>
        <target>(jeho mníšské jméno), se narodil na</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>full moon</source>
        <target>úplněk</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>April 9,</source>
        <target>9-ho dubna</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>1990 in 150 kilometers from Lumbini, the Ratanpuri village, Nepal</source>
        <target>1990, 150 km od Lumbini, v nepálské vesnici Ratanpuri</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>His parents are farmers. His mother,</source>
        <target>Jeho rodiče jsou farmáři. Matka,</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Maya Devi</source>
        <target>Mája Déví</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>was married at 12. Amazingly during delivery when only baby's head was just out of the womb, he let out a cry, that echoed in village.</source>
        <target> byla vdaná ve svých 12-ti letech. Zvláštním způsobem, když hlavička jejího dítěte Rama vylezla, ten vydal tak hlasitý křik, že se to ozývalo v celé vesnici.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He started his meditation on May 16, 2005.</source>
        <target>Svou meditaci zahájil 16. května 2005.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>After 7 months Ram was bitten by a snake and monks covered him with curtain. After five days it was opened and Ram spoke:</source>
        <target>Po sedmi měsících jej uštknul had a mniši jej od pohledu veřejnosti ukryli za záclonou. Po pěti dnech se záclona odsunula a Ram řekl:</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>«...A snake bit me but I do not need treatment. I need 6 years of deep meditation.»</source>
        <target>«Uštknul mě had, ale nepotřebuji ošetření. Musím se věnovat 6 let trvající hluboké meditaci.»</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>During 9 months he was motionless meditating near the Buddhist’s sacred tree without any food or water.</source>
        <target>Devět měsíců seděl nehybně v meditaci pod buddhistickým posvátným stromem, a to bez jakéhokoli jídla anebo pití.</target>
      </trans-unit>     
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On January 19, 2006 he spontaneously</source>
        <target>19-ho ledna 2006 Ram Bahadur Bomdžon spontánně</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje in fire</source>
        <target>Palden Dordže v ohni</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>combusted</source>
        <target>vzplál</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>, burning off the clothes he has worn for nine months but leaving no scars. After some time in a very soft voice he called for his brother. He asked for a red robe to be thrown over him, he wrapped this close over his body, and he said, let him concentrate on his meditation and do not disturb him.</source>
        <target> v meditaci, což spálilo šaty které měl na sobě po devět měsíců, ale nezpůsobilo mu žádné popáleniny. Po nějaké době se ozval velmi jemným hlasem, a požádal o zavolání bratra. Požádal jej, aby jej zakryl róbou bordové barvy, kterou pak obtočil kolem svého těla a požádal aby jej nechali soustředit se na svou meditaci, a aby jej nevyrušovali.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>There is stories of miracles: a girl and a young man had gained the</source>
        <target>Objevili se nějaké příhody o zázracích: mladá dívka a také jeden mladý muž získali</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>miracle</source>
        <target>zázrak</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>power of speech</source>
        <target>schopnost řeči</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>although they could not speak...</source>
        <target>, přestože dříve byli němí...</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Read More about Buddha Boy</source>
        <target>Přečtěte si více o Palden Dordže</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Read more...</source>
        <target>Více...</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Gautama Buddha</source>
        <target>Gautama Buddha</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Siddhattha Gautama was born in 563 BCE in Lumbini (modern day Nepal). His mother was Maya Devi but she died in seven days after his delivery.</source>
        <target>Siddharta Gautama se narodil r. 563 před n. l. v Lumbini (v současnosti Nepál). Jeho matka se jmenovala Maya Devi, ale zemřela 7 dní po porodu.</target>
      </trans-unit>      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>At the age of 29 he left his home and family to become a monk. Then, sitting under a tree he vowed never to arise until he had found the Truth.</source>
        <target>Když Siddhartovi bylo 29 let, opustil svůj domov a rodinu, aby se stal asketou. Když seděl pod stromem pípal, předsevzal si že nevstane pokud neobjeví Pravdu.</target>
      </trans-unit>      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>At the age of 35 in the fifth lunar month he attaining enlightenment. Gautama, from then on, was known as the Buddha or "Awakened One." Buddha is also sometimes translated as "The Enlightened One."</source>
        <target>Osvícení dosáhl v 35-ti letech, v pátém lunárním měsíci. Od této doby byl Gautama znám jako Buddha, "Probuzený". Slovo Buddha se také překládá jako "Osvícený".</target>
      </trans-unit>  

    </body>
  </file>
</xliff>