<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<xliff version="1.0">
  <file original="global" source-language="en" datatype="plaintext">
    <body>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Save Nepal Tapasvi Forest</source>
        <target>Сохраним Лес Тапасви в Непале</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Preserve and Expand Nepal Dharmic Forest</source>
        <target>Защитим и расширим Лес Дхармы Непала</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>A destructive attitude towards the forest has already led to a number of irreversible environmental disasters in various regions of our planet.</source>
        <target>Хищническое отношение к лесным богатствам уже привело к множеству необратимых экологических катастроф в различных регионах нашей планеты.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>As is happening all over the planet, forests in Nepal are being cut and polluted for monetary gains, which leads to disappearance of birds, animals and plants.</source>
        <target>Как и везде на планете, леса в Непале вырубаются и загрязняются ради наживы, что приводит к исчезновению птиц, животных и растений.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Nepal has been classified by the United Nations Environmental Programme (UNEP) as the highest risk zone in Asia in terms of the ecological crisis.</source>
        <target>Непал был классифицирован Программой Организации Объединенных Наций по окружающей среде (ЮНЕП) как зона повышенного риска в Азии с точки зрения экологического состояния.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Now we have the opportunity to protect the flora and fauna of a pristine jungle in Nepal.</source>
        <target>Сейчас у нас есть возможность защитить флору и фауну девственных джунглей Непала.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Maha Sambodhi Dharma Sangha has been meditating for six years (2005-2011) “for the happiness and well-being of the world, for the jungle, for conservation of plants” (</source>
        <target>Маха Самбодхи Дхарма Сангха медитировал в течение шести лет (2005–2011) «ради счастья и благополучия мира, ради джунглей и животных, ради сохранения растений» (</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Discovery Channel Documentary</source>
        <target>Фильм Дискавери</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>.)</source>
        <target>).</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>The jungle area surrounding Tapasvi’s (spiritual practitioner) meditation site is an ancient land.</source>
        <target>Джунгли, окружающие место медитации Тапасви (духовно практикующий) – это древнейшие земли.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Halkhoriya is the historical forest: some events, described in the the oldest eposes (Ramayana, Mahabharata), took place here; the divine avatar Ram and legendary warrior Arjuna came to this place thousands years ago.</source>
        <target>Халкория – это исторический лес: некоторые события, описанные в старинных эпосах (Рамаяна, Махабхарата), происходили здесь; божественный аватар Рам и легендарный воин Арджуна были в этом месте тысячи лет назад.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>A very small part of this jungle has been already legalized as The Dharmic Forest (Dharma – universal and cosmic truth, righteous duty, virtuous path, liberating law.)</source>
        <target>Очень небольшая часть джунглей уже утверждена как Лес Дхармы (Дхарма – универсальная или абсолютная истина, праведный долг, добродетельный путь, освобождающий закон).</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>It is forbidden to cut trees or grass, kill living beings or pollute the area inside of this area.</source>
        <target>Здесь запрещается рубить деревья и косить траву, убивать живых существ или загрязнять окружающую среду.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>If the whole area were given The Dharmic Forest status, this would allow it become a safe sanctuary for numerous beautiful birds, animals and plants and help in their conservation.</source>
        <target>Если всей территории джунглей будет присвоен статус Леса Дхармы, это позволит этому месту стать безопасным убежищем для бесчисленного множества красивейших птиц, животных и растений и помочь их сохранению.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Destiny of the living creatures and plants is in your hands.</source>
        <target>Судьба живых существ и растений в ваших руках.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Now it's your turn...</source>
        <target>Дело за вами...</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Take action</source>
        <target>Действовать</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Stay indifferent</source>
        <target>Ничего не делать</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>We, the undersigned, respectfully submit to the Ministry of Forests and Soil Conservation, Nepal, this petition for due consideration to grant the legal status of "Dharmic Forest" to the entire jungle area including Pathlaiya, Halkoriya, and Ratanpuri. This petition is also addressed to all Citizens of Nepal whose proactive and loving participation is urgently needed by this beautiful part of Nepal's Nature now being threatened.</source>
        <target>Мы, нижеподписавшиеся, с почтением направляем эту петицию в Министерство лесного хозяйства и охраны почв Непала для рассмотрения и присвоения законного статуса «Леса Дхармы» территории, включающей джунгли Патлайя, Халкория и Ратанпури. Эта петиция также направлена ко всем гражданам Непала, чьё активное и наполненное любовью участие требуется незамедлительно этой красивейшей части природы Непала, которая сейчас находится под угрозой.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Instructions: fill out your details and click "Sign petition" button and then click it again on the next page to approve signing.</source>
        <target>Подсказка: введите данные и нажмите кнопку "Sign Petition", затем на следующей странице нажмите данную кнопку повторно, чтобы подтвердить подписание.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>View signers</source>
        <target>Список подписавшихся</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
<!-- утф -->
    </body>
  </file>
</xliff>