<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<xliff version="1.0">
  <file original="global" source-language="en" datatype="plaintext">
    <body>

<!-- showSuccess -->
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Family and Childhood</source>
        <target>家庭和童年</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>School and Religious Education</source>
        <target>学校和宗教教育</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje's Illness</source>
        <target>拉姆生病</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje Disappears</source>
        <target>拉姆失踪</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Meditation Begins</source>
        <target>开始禅修</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Snakebite and Miracles</source>
        <target>被蛇咬伤和奇迹发生</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Wandering to Bara district</source>
        <target>游荡在巴哈地区</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Meditating in pit</source>
        <target>地下室禅修</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Preaching in Halkhoriya jungle</source>
        <target>丛林布道</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Buddhist background</source>
        <target>佛教背景</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Feats of inedia</source>
        <target>辟谷之路</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Reappearance in Ratanpur jungle</source>
        <target>重现丛林</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>New Appearance in 2009</source>
        <target>2009年新面貌</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Sambodhi Dharma Sangha (earlier Palden Dorje, born Ram Bahadur Bomjan) was born on April 10, 1990 between 2:25am and 4am (information on date and time is still controversial and will be checked and clarified) in Ratanpur village, Bara district, Nepal.</source>
        <target>拉姆.巴哈杜尔.班坚于1990年四月九日生于尼泊尔巴拉区的班吉尔拉坦普里村</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Ram’s parents are farmers. His mother, Maya Devi was married at 12.  She had 5 sons and 4 daughters.  Ram was her third son.  When she was in her pregnancy, she found she was unable to eat meat without becoming ill.  The son, whom she named Ram, would not eat meat.  He would leave the house for long intervals from an early age.</source>
        <target>拉姆的父母都是农民。他的母亲玛雅黛菲12岁结婚，有5个儿子和4个女儿。拉姆是第三个孩子。当玛雅黛菲怀孕的时候，她发现自己不能吃肉，如果吃肉就会生病。拉姆出生后也不能吃肉。拉姆很小的时候就离开家去了很远的地方。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Ram was always pleased to see a lama or a holy person and fastidiously imitated them.  He often seemed to be lost in thought and spoke little.  Whenever someone spoke to him, he would reply with a smile and would treat people of all ages equally.</source>
        <target>拉姆从小就喜欢看到喇嘛或者圣人，而且很喜欢亲近他们。他看上去经常陷入沉思，而且很少说话。当和别人交谈时他总是微笑着回答，并且对所有人都平等地对待。</target>
      </trans-unit>
  
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>According to his family and neighbors, Ram Bomjan often acted differently from his childhood friends, frequently observing other people in worship and praying himself. He has been described as being born with a peaceful nature, and would never get into a fight or kill an animal. Beginning at the age of five he only took leftovers for food, and went hungry if there was nothing.</source>
        <target>他的家人和邻居回忆道，拉姆班坚经常表现得和他的同龄朋友们不一样，他常常观察其他人膜拜时的情形。他被描述为具有平和天性，从不打架或杀生。自从他5岁开始，他只吃剩下的食物，如果已经没有了，他就饿着。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He took his studies seriously and rarely played with other children, choosing instead to remain alone. He spent his time reading scriptures, meditating and worshipping the pipal tree which seemed to bring him joy. Seeing this behavior, Ram’s father sent him to study the scriptures of Lama Chhyoi with Samden Lama in their village.  After that Ram decided to embrace a religious life.</source>
        <target>他很认真的学习并且选择独处，很少和小孩子玩。他花时间在读经，禅修，和膜拜菩提树，这些都带给他快乐。看到这种行为，拉姆的父母送他去村里的萨姆登那里去学习经文。在那之后，拉姆决定选择了信仰的生活。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He was accepted into the monkhood by Som Bahadur Lama of Sudha, Ward 8 of Chitwan Village Development Committee.</source>
        <target>他被桑巴杜喇嘛录取为一名僧侣，并且被8名奇望村发展委员会成员监护。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Som Bahadur Lama said the following of his ward: “He was obedient. He never said ‘no’ to my word. He was friendly and sociable and he received education in that manner. He used to say frequently that his attention was much more drawn towards meditation than towards reading books.”</source>
        <target>一些巴哈杜尔喇嘛回忆他说：“他很听话。他从来不对我的话说不。他很友好也很随和，就这样他在那里接受教育。他经常说他更关注禅修胜于读书。”</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He was granted the initiation of</source>
        <target>他被传授了</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Panchasheel</source>
        <target>“五誓言”。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Panchasheel is a Sanskrit word for a Buddhist initiation consisting of five vows, which are as follows:</source>
        <target>“五誓言”是梵语，代表佛门最初包括的五个誓愿：</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must not kill animals (it is preferable to be vegetarian)</source>
        <target>不杀害动物（最好成为素食者）</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must not steal</source>
        <target>不偷盗</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must not lie</source>
        <target>不妄语</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must refrain from sexual misconduct</source>
        <target>不看他人过错</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must not take intoxicating substances</source>
        <target>不用毒品</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Ram was initiated along with a group of nine other students. Ram refused to have his hair cut before the initiation, which was the common custom. It was after this initiation that Ram received the name,</source>
        <target>拉姆开始加入一个９个学生的小组。拉姆拒绝了在入门前剃头的习俗。入门后，拉姆得到了法名</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje</source>
        <target>巴登.多杰</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>It was the custom for the initiates to meditate for up to a month in a cave. Som Bahadur Lama was surprised at the ease with which Palden Dorje seemed to adapt to the situation requiring little sustenance. It was then that he realized that the boy had a natural talent for deep and prolonged meditation.</source>
        <target>根据惯例，最初禅修要在洞穴中呆最多一个月。所以巴哈杜尔拉马对看到拉姆只吃一点东西而且很适应环境而感到惊讶。此后，他意识到这个孩子对甚深禅定有天赋。</target>
	  </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>After completing his Buddhist education for two years, all nine initiates went to Lumbini, the birthplace of Lord Buddha, for sightseeing. Palden Dorje seemed utterly taken by this place and it seemed to deepen his religious resolve. The other eight initiates returned but he refused to return. Instead, he went to Dehradun to further his religious education with the Gurus of Dehradun. Later he returned to Nepal to the beautiful lakeside city of Pokhara.</source>
        <target>在完成２年的佛学教育后，所有９个入门者都去瞻仰蓝毗尼-释迦牟尼的出生之地。巴登.多杰看上去完全被这个地方接纳，而且他更加深了他的信仰决心。其他８个初学员都回家了，但是他没有。相反地，他去了迪西拉登深造。后来返回美丽的湖边城市博克拉。</target>
	  </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Here it was that Palden Dorje became ill, and was unable to move his lower body.  Distressed, his teachers sent him home to recover.  During this time, Palden Dorje implored his family not to sacrifice any animals or take any alcohol otherwise further complications would arise.  He got better, but was still limping when he disappeared from his home the night of  May 16, 2005.</source>
        <target>从迪西拉登返回家里后，他生病了，不能挪动下肢。他的老师悲伤地送他去治疗。在这段时间，巴登.多杰肯求他的家人不要杀害任何动物或者喝酒，不然会有并发症。他的病好了，但当他在２００５年５月１６日晚离开家的时候仍然有点蹒跚。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>When his mother became aware of the situation, she alerted the village, and everyone joined in the search for him.  A local boy claimed to have seen him while he was shaking a mango tree.  Palden Dorje had come up and picked up a mango, and stepped fully clothed into the river. “I thought you had disappeared,” – the boy remarked to Palden Dorje.</source>
        <target>当他的妈妈发现这个情况，她告诉村里每一个人来一起寻找他。一个当地男孩说他见到他在摇一个芒果树。巴登多杰走向河边。男孩对他喊：“我以为你失踪了”</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>“Have I?” – Palden Dorje  replied. – “You’d better go home, and be careful not to touch me.” The boy ran home to tell his story, but nobody believed him at first.  Palden Dorje’s relatives went to the ravine.  Palden Dorje smiled at them when they found him as was his habit.  They told him to come home.  “I’ll go home at four o’clock,” – Palden Dorje said.  His family decided it would be wise to keep an eye on him, and so some of his siblings stayed with him.</source>
        <target>“我么？”巴登多杰回答。＂你最好回家，小心别碰倒我＂。男孩跑回家告诉了这件事，当时起初没人相信他。巴登多杰的亲人跑去河边。当人们发现他，巴登多杰像往常一样对他们微笑。他们告诉他回家。巴登多杰说：＂我会４点钟回家＂。他家人觉得最好看着他,所以留了他的兄弟陪着他。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>At four o’clock, he picked up a couple of mangoes and began to eat one.  He told his little brother to bring him water, rice, his lama robes, a rosary and a picture of Buddha.  His little brother obeyed.  Palden Dorje’s sister came to tell Palden Dorje to come home at once.  Seeing how emaciated he looked from his previous  illness, she cried and begged him to come home.  Palden Dorje told her to stop crying, and she went home.</source>
        <target>四点钟时，他开始吃他摘的一个芒果。他告诉他的弟弟去拿一些水，米，和他的喇嘛袍，一串念珠和一张佛的照片。他弟弟照办。巴登多杰的姐姐来告诉他回家。看到他比生病前还憔悴，她哭了，乞求他回家。巴登多杰告诉她不要哭，她回家了。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Then Palden Dorje, sitting in a meditative posture seemed to go into a trance.  He began to ask himself questions and answer them out loud. The other villagers came and told Palden Dorje to stop being silly and come home.</source>
        <target>然后巴登多杰以禅定的姿势坐着，并且看上去要昏沉了。他开始问自己问题，然后大声地回答这些问题。其他村民过来告诉巴登多杰不要犯傻回家去。</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>They feared he must be ill or crazy.  When Palden Dorje’s older brother touched him, Palden Dorje’s body became exceedingly hot and turned red. “Please leave me alone, or one of us may die,” – Palden Dorje said. – “If anyone disturbs me or my things at midnight, I will have to meditate for 20 years, but if all goes well, I will meditate for 6 years.”</source>
        <target>他们害怕他一定生病了或者疯了。当巴登多杰的哥哥碰到他的时候，巴登多杰的身体开始变得十分热，变成了红色。“请不要管我，我们中的一个可能要死了”巴登多杰说：“如果任何人在午夜打扰我或者打扰我的事情，我就会不得不禅修２０年。但是，如果一切进行顺利，我就会禅修６年”</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Then Palden Dorje, followed by his brother, and at a distance by the villagers set out to find a good meditation  place in the forest. His parents insisted he take some food and water with him.  Finally, he reached his destination  at 11:00 AM on May 18, 2005. This was the day the villagers of Ratanpur celebrated</source>
        <target>。然后，巴登多杰跟着他的哥哥去村民们为他找到的适合禅修的地方。他父母坚持要他带食物和水。最后，他于２００５年５月１８日上午１１点来到目的地。这是这个村子庆祝卫塞节的日子。</target>
      </trans-unit>      

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vesak</source>
        <target>http://ru.wikipedia.org/wiki/Весак</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Buddha Jayanti (Vesak)</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He settled himself under a pipal tree, having offered 10 kinds of fruit to the picture of Buddha.</source>
        <target>他安定在一个菩提树下，为佛的照片供奉了１０种水果。</target>
      </trans-unit>      

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>About 30 villagers saw where Palden Dorje was meditating, and they left an offering of over a thousand rupees as was the custom at Buddha Jayanti.  On that night at 12:00,  some pranksters came to disturb Palden Dorje and steal the offering.  They quarreled over the money, and later accused each other in front of the villagers.  Having confessed, they asked Palden Dorje’s forgiveness.</source>
        <target>大概３０个村民看到巴登多杰在打坐禅修，他们留下了１０００多卢比来供佛。当天晚上１２点，一些恶作剧的人来打扰巴登多杰，而且偷走了供奉品。他们因为钱而吵架，最后在前面的村庄互相举报。他们承认过错，希望巴登多杰原谅。</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>So Palden Dorje left the first meditation place and went north on the 24th of May, 2005.  At that time he gave six pipal leaves to his second elder brother telling him to keep them in oil.  He said that as long as his family kept the leaves, all would be well.  His relatives cried when he left.</source>
        <target>因此巴登多杰离开第一个禅修地于２００５年５月２４日向北方走去。那时候，他给他的二哥６个菩提叶子告诉他把叶子放油里面。他说只要家人保护好叶子，一切都会平安。他离开时他的亲人大哭。</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Again the villagers were concerned about Palden Dorje’s whereabouts, and in the late afternoon, a cowherd had seen him in his new meditation site. The villagers sent some of his family to go and bring him home.  But Palden Dorje refused and  moved to another pipal tree in the east.</source>
        <target>村民们对他的去向十分关心。午后，放牛人看到他在新的地方了。村民派人去把他亲人招来让他回家。但是巴登多杰拒绝了，并且去了东边一个菩提树下。</target>
      </trans-unit>      

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje told his family that he must continue to meditate at all costs.  He drew a boundary around his meditation area, and the villagers and his relatives built a fence for him. More and more crowds gathered at the site, so Palden Dorje ordered that a hut be built and sealed with plastic on all sides wherein he remained for 15 days. After that Palden Dorje said, “I have received some energy so that I may now meditate under a tree outside”.</source>
        <target>巴登多杰告诉他的家人他必须不惜代价继续禅修。他在禅修地画了一个界限。村民和他的家人建了一个栅栏。越来越多的人群来到这里，所以巴登多杰命令建立一个棚屋，周围用塑料封住，他在里面呆了１５天。之后巴登多杰说：“我已经储存了力量，我现在可以在树外打坐了。”		
		</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>There was a terrible drought in the village. Palden Dorje told them to pray to a snake god and after 5 days, it started raining. In the 75th day of meditation, he opened the eyes and asked his elder brother to call him by the words: “Om Namó Gurú Búddha Gyáni”.</source>
        <target>那时村里有严重的旱灾。巴登多杰告诉他们，向蛇神祈祷，5天之后开始下雨了。在禅修第75天，他告诉他的哥哥叫他“Om Namo Guru Buddha Gyani”</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He returned to his meditation. Since that day he was addressed as</source>
        <target>他继续禅修。从那天之后，他被叫做</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>“Om Namo Guru Buddha Gyani”</source>
        <target>“Om Namo Guru Buddha Gyani”</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>(Hail to the Master of the Wisdom of Buddha.)</source>
        <target>（向佛的大智慧觉悟者致敬）</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On August 18, 2005, Palden Dorje called together his friends who were lamas.  They asked him how it was that Palden Dorje was surviving without water. Palden Dorje replied that two snake gods protected him from either side.  That day Palden Dorje also changed his clothes and wore a white cloth called Ngag.</source>
        <target>在2005年8月18日，巴登多杰把自己的喇嘛朋友们召集到一起。他们问他没有水的情况下怎么活下来的。巴登多杰回复说，两个蛇神在两侧保护他。那天，巴登多杰还换了衣服，穿了一种叫做Ngag的白色衣服。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On November 6, 2005 snake bit Palden Dorje, and Palden Dorje’s body was poisoned. Palden Dorje sweated more than two liters while he continued to meditate, and thus he overcame the poison.  Palden Dorje’s followers believe that on that day he was enlightened, for the Bodhisattva has the ability to survive attached to a tree, soil and stone, to digest snake poison, to be unaffected by the wind and to understand the language of all creatures.</source>
        <target>2005年11月6日，蛇神授予巴登多杰一个仪式，那可能会帮助他到达佛的境界。 Bodhisattva 然后蛇神咬了巴登多杰，巴登多杰的身体中了毒。巴登多杰在禅修中流了2升多的汗水。之后他克服了毒素。巴登多杰的追随者相信从那天起，他有能力能处于树，石头，土地的环境中，并且不怕剧毒，以及能够理解其他生物的语言。</target>
      </trans-unit>           

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On November 8, 2005, Palden Dorje told the people that he did not have the energy of a Buddha, and he asked them not to publicize him as an incarnation of Buddha.</source>
        <target>2005年11月8日，巴登多杰告诉人们他并没有佛的能力。他告诉大家不要叫他佛陀。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On November 11, 2005 a bright light appeared shining from Palden Dorje’s head.  His followers cried with joy and became even more fervent.</source>
        <target>2005年11月11日，一束明亮的光照在巴登多杰的头上。他的追随者高兴的大哭然后更加狂热。</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>“Leave me in peace, and there will soon be peace in the country,” – Palden Dorje said. However crowds ever increased and people chanted and set up a market place, according to Radio HBC 94 FM who visited the site on December 10, 2005. The crowds were kept at a distance of about 50 meters. All witnesses claimed that Palden Dorje neither ate, drank or left to relieve himself.  He just sat and meditated under the pipal tree. Baffled onlookers were ever increasing.</source>
        <target>“给我安静，很快国家也会在平和中“巴登多杰说道。然而，根据HBC 94FM 广播电台在2005年12月10日所说，大众越来越多，然们咏唱，还建立了一个市场。人群被隔离在50米之外。所有眼见者都说巴登班杰从来不吃，不喝，也不会离开放松自己。他只是坐在菩提树下禅定。观众们继续增加。</target>
      </trans-unit>      

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>There were stories of miracles: a</source>
        <target>曾有个关于奇迹的故事：一个</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>girl</source>
        <target>哑巴女孩</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>and a young man had gained the power of speech although they could not speak.</source>
        <target>和一个哑巴年轻男人得到了能讲话的力量。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>After about ten months of meditation, Palden Dorje went missing on 11 March 2006. He gave no explanation, and some believed he had been abducted. His followers theorized that he went deeper into the woods to look for a quieter place to meditate.</source>
        <target>在１０个月的禅修之后，巴登多杰于２００６年１１月３日消失。他没有留下任何解释，有人相信他被绑架了。他的追随者在理论上相信他进入了深林寻找安静禅修之地。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Police abandoned a search for him after the possibility of foul play was eliminated. Suspecting money laundering, the authorities froze the bank account of the local committee managing the crowds, which had gathered more than Rs. 600,000 ($7950), but they found no evidence.</source>
        <target>在排除恶作剧的情况下，警察开始寻找他。怀疑洗钱，管理者冻结了当地管理群众委员会的银行账户。账户里有大概$７９５０元。然而，警察并没有找到任何洗钱的证据。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 19 March, a group of Palden Dorje's followers met with him about 2 miles (3 kilometers) southwest of his meditation site. They say they spoke to him for thirty minutes, during which Palden Dorje said: "There is no peace here" and that he would return in six years, which would be in 2011 or 2012. He left a message for his parents telling them not to worry.</source>
        <target>在３月１９日，一群巴登多杰的追随者在他禅修地大概３千米西南方向找到了他。他们和他交谈了３０分钟，在交谈中，巴登多杰说：“这里不安静”。他会在6年内回来，大概在2011或者2012年。他给父母留下口信，告诉他们不要担心。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 25 December 2006, villagers in Bara district spotted Palden Dorje meditating. He was carrying a sword for protection in the jungle, reminding reporters that "Even Gautama Buddha had to protect himself," and claimed to have eaten nothing but herbs in the interim.</source>
        <target>2006年12月25日，巴哈地区村民聚集在巴登多杰禅修地。他带了一把剑在丛林护身，提醒记者们“即使他也要保护自己”然后承认在休息时吃了一些植物。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He reiterated his six year commitment to Buddhist devotion, and said he would allow people to come and observe him, as long as they remained at some distance and didn't bother him. When a reporter pointed out that pilgrims to his meditation site would be making donations in his name, he asked for the donations to not be abused or used for commercial purposes. A new wave of visitors came to see him and pray at his new meditation spot. On 8 March 2007 he left Bara district to again find a quieter place to meditate.</source>
        <target>他重申了他6年使命，然后说他同意人们来观察他，只要他们保持一定距离，而且不要打扰他。当一个报道者指出，有朝拜者为他捐钱时，他要求不要乱用捐款，而且不要用于商业用途。新的一批追随者来到他的禅修地。2007年3月8日，他离开禅修地区，又找到一个安静的地方继续禅修。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 26 March 2007, Inspector Rameshwor Yadav of the Area Police Post Nijgadh, found Palden Dorje inside a bunker-like ditch seven feet square. A police team under Yadav's command had gone to the place after word had spread of Palden Dorje meditating underground. “His face was clean and hair was combed well,” – Yadav said.</source>
        <target>2007年3月26日，当时全世界都宣传他在地下禅修，警察小组在调查员Rameshwor Yadava的命令下，去了地下找他。那是一个7平方英尺的类似于沟壑的地堡中。Yadav说：“他看上去很干净，头发也整齐”</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>According to him, the bunker had been cemented from all sides and fitted with a tiled roof. Indra Lama, a local deployed as Palden Dorje's caretaker since the beginning of his intensive meditation, said the bunker was prepared per Palden Dorje's request. “After granting audience a week ago, he expressed his desire to meditate inside the ground; so we built it,” – he said.</source>
        <target>据他所说，地堡四周被挡住了，上面有个屋顶。印第喇嘛，一个当地自从巴登多杰开始禅修救保护他的人，说地下堡根据巴登多杰的吩咐准备的。“在一周前和大众见面时，他表达了地下禅修的愿望，所以他们就照做了。”</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 2 August 2007, Palden Dorje</source>
        <target>2007年8月2日，巴登多杰</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>addressed a large crowd</source>
        <target>在尼泊尔南方巴哈地区的哈罗瑞丛林中，会见了大量群众。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>in Halkhoriya jungle in Bara district of southern Nepal. The Namo Buddha Tapoban Committee, which is devoted to looking after Palden Dorje, assembled the meeting.</source>
        <target>塔坡班佛陀委员会是一个致力于照顾巴登多杰的组织，它组织了聚会。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>A notice about the boy's first-ever preaching was broadcast by a local FM radio station, and the committee also invited people by telephone. Around three thousand people gathered to listen to Palden Dorje's address. A video was made of the event. According to Upendra Lamichhane, a blogger who wrote an article and took pictures of the meeting, Palden Dorje's message was, "The only way we can save this nation is through spirituality".</source>
        <target>当地FM广播电台传播了巴登多杰要做第一个开示的消息，委员会还通过电话邀请人参加。大约3000人聚集到一起听了巴登多杰的开示。并依此制作了一个录像。一个博客写手Upendra Lamichhane写了一个文章还照了会议。巴登多杰传达的信息是：“拯救世界唯一的途径就是灵修。”</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>This was his speech:</source>
        <target>以下就是他的开示:</target>
      </trans-unit>     

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje is a member of the</source>
        <target>巴登多杰是</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Tamang</source>
        <target>大蒙族的一员，</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>community, of which a majority practices</source>
        <target>大蒙族主要学习藏传佛教。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Vajrayana Buddhism</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje's story gained popularity because it resembled a legend from the Jataka Nidanakatha about</source>
        <target>巴登多杰的故事十分受欢迎因为它看上去很像《本生因缘记》（Jataka Nidanakatha，乃本生经的序论与佛传）</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Gautama Buddha's</source>
        <target>中关于释迦牟尼佛的开导。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>enlightenment, so much so that some devotees claimed Palden Dorje was the reincarnation of a Buddha.</source>
        <target>很多人相信巴登多杰是佛的转世。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>However, on 8 November 2005 Dorje arose and said: “Tell the people not to call me a Buddha. I don't have the Buddha's energy. I am at the level of a rimpoche.” A rimpoche is a teacher, which indicates he believes he has achieved a significant amount. He said that he will need six more years of meditation before he may become a Buddha.</source>
        <target>然而，2005年11月8日，巴登多杰呼吁大家：“告诉人们不要称呼我佛陀。我并没有佛陀的力量。我只是仁波切的境界。”仁波切是对上师的尊称，这标志着他相信他已经得到了一种显著成就。他说还需要打坐6年才有可能成为佛。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>According to his followers, Palden Dorje may have reached the stage of a</source>
        <target>他的追随者觉得，巴登多杰可能已经在佛法的路上到了一个佛的阶层</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Bodhisattva </source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>a person on the path to attaining full enlightenment or buddhahood for the benefit of all sentient beings. According to the historical Buddha, Gautama Buddha, there were innumerable Buddhas before him and infinite Buddhas to come. Proponents also claim that Palden Dorje might also be</source>
        <target>，并且完全可以为众生开示。根据佛教历史，在释迦牟尼佛之前和之后都有无数的佛曾近来过或者将要来到。信徒们觉得巴登多杰</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Maitreya</source>
        <target>可能是弥勒尊佛的化身，</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Bodhisattva, the predicted successor to the historical Buddha.</source>
        <target>弥勒尊佛是下一个将要来到的佛。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>His mother's name is Maya Devi Tamang, the same first name as Buddha's mother. It is reported that his mother fainted when she found out that her son intended to meditate for an indefinite period.</source>
        <target>他的母亲的名字叫做玛雅黛菲唐安，其中名字和释迦牟尼佛的母亲的名字相同。据报道，当他的母亲发现她的儿子要无定期的打坐时，她昏倒了。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Those who have called him the "reincarnation of Buddha" have been criticised. Gautama Buddha taught that after</source>
        <target>那些称呼他为转世活佛的人受到了严厉的批评。释迦牟尼佛曾经交待过</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>parinirvana</source>
        <target>圆寂之后，</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>there is no more rebirth, therefore it is impossible to be a "reincarnation of Buddha", but it is possible to be another Buddha, another who has attained, or will attain, enlightenment.</source>
        <target>不会重来。因此他不可能是转世活佛，但是有可能是另一尊佛，一尊可能已经成就或者将要成就的佛。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>An average human being who stops drinking will die of dehydration in three to four days. According to the Guinness Book of Records the longest time a human has survived without water is 18 days. Palden Dorje, on the other hand, does not appear to break his meditation to eat or drink.</source>
        <target>一个普通人断水后将会在3到4天内渴死。吉尼斯记载一个人在没有水的情况下最长活18天。例外的，巴登多杰在连续禅修中没有进食。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje was observed not to leave the tree at least during the daytime, but nobody was allowed to approach him too closely. Between 5:00 p.m. and 5:00 a.m. nobody was allowed to see him, and a screen was erected for that purpose. Many people speculated that he ate and drank water during that time.</source>
        <target>据观察，巴登多杰在白天没有离开菩提树，但是没有人被准许去接近他。在下午5点和早上5点之间，没有人照看他，有摄像头记录着。有人投机地猜测他在那个时候进食。
</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Some supporters believe that discussions of</source>
        <target>一些支持者认为这种争论</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inedia</source>
        <target>http://blog.artnn.ru/2006/09/30/solntseedyi-kto-takie-solntseedyi/</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>inedia</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>are irrelevant, and that the ability to sit nearly motionless in the same position day after day, with no regard for extremes of weather including a cold winter and a monsoon season, is notable. For example, American writer George Saunders visited Palden Dorje and observed him through a single night, and was impressed by Palden Dorje's perfectly still stature, even during an evening climate that seemed unbearably cold to the much better clothed journalist.</source>
        <target>是无关紧要的。这种可以坐在一个地方保持同一种姿势日以继夜，无论风吹日晒，寒冬酷暑，的能力已经十分令人关注。比如：美国作家乔治桑德来探访巴登多杰，通过整晚观察，被他可以难以忍受的寒冷夜晚保持完美的静坐姿势而打动。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>In December 2005, a nine-member government committee led by Gunjaman Lama watched Palden Dorje carefully for 48 hours and observed him not to take any food or water during that time. A video recording was also made of this test. However, they were unable to approach closer than 3 meters or take readings of his vital signs. The Nepalese government planned a more careful scientific study, but the plan was never carried out.</source>
        <target>在２００５年１２月，９个政府官员在甘迦玛喇嘛的带领下观察巴登多杰４８个小时，并且观察到他并没有吃任何食物和水。一个录像也证明了这一点。然而，他们不能靠近３米之内。因此，尼泊尔政府正在计划一个更加科学的研究，不过目前还未开始。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>In 2007, the Discovery Channel produced a documentary titled</source>
        <target>在２００７年，探索频道制作了一个名为：“灵修少年”</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>The Boy With Divine Powers</source>
        <target>的节目。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On their first, four-day attempt, the film crew was required to stay outside a guarded barbed-wire fence, and their camera's infrared capabilities did not pick up evidence of a body at the base of the tree where Palden Dorje sat during their non-stop recording. On a second attempt a few weeks later, however, the film crew was able to film Palden Dorje continuously for 96 hours, day and night, during which time he did not drink any fluids or eat any food. According to scientists on the documentary, an average person would be expected to die from kidney failure after four days without drinking any fluids. The boy showed no signs of classical physical deterioration caused by dehydration. A close inspection by the film crew of the area around the tree where Palden Dorje was sitting revealed no hidden food supply or water pipes.</source>
        <target>在他们前４天的工作中，一个电影工作小组按照要求在栅栏外面拍摄，他们不停工作的录像机无法拍摄巴登多杰一直坐在树下的纪录。几周之后第二次努力下，工作人员能够拍摄到巴登多杰连续９６个小时的日日夜夜中，他没有吃任何事物和喝水。根据科学记载，平均一个人缺水会在４天死于肾衰竭。这个男孩证明没有任何缺水引起的身体不适。通过在树周围工作人员进一步调查，证明巴登多杰在静坐中没有藏匿任何食物或者水源。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 10 November 2008, Palden Dorje</source>
        <target>在２００８年１１月１０日，巴登多杰</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>reappeared and spoke</source>
        <target>重新出现而且</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>to a group of devotees in the remote jungle of Ratanpur, 150 km (95 miles) southeast of Kathmandu, near Nijgadh. His hair was shoulder-length and his body was wrapped in a white cloth.</source>
        <target>对距加德满都正南大约１５０公里（９５英里）的“尼吉加德镇”的拉塔普里丛林里的信徒们讲话。他头发齐肩，身裹白布。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>His devotees believe he attained enlightenment at Bodh Gaya in Bihar, which borders Nepal – the place where Siddartha Gautama attained enlightenment.</source>
        <target>他的信徒相信他在比尼泊尔旁边的比哈尔得到了佛果。那里也是悉达多释迦牟尼证果之地。加德满都龙树研究所的萨迦说他还没有调查这个自从２００５年就在树林中度过１０个月的男孩。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>biography_translated_by</source>
        <target>Sandy</target>
      </trans-unit>

    </body>
  </file>
</xliff>