<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<xliff version="1.0">
  <file original="global" source-language="en" datatype="plaintext">
    <body>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Family and Childhood</source>
        <target>家族と子供時代</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>School and Religious Education</source>
        <target>学業及び宗教教育</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje's Illness</source>
        <target>パルデン・ドルジェの病気</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje Disappears</source>
        <target>パルデン・ドルジェ姿を消す</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Meditation Begins</source>
        <target>瞑想が始まる</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Snakebite and Miracles</source>
        <target>蛇に咬まれたこととその奇跡</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Wandering to Bara district</source>
        <target>バラ地区をさまよって</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Meditating in pit</source>
        <target>穴の中での瞑想</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Preaching in Halkhoriya jungle</source>
        <target>ハルコーリアのジャングルでの説教</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Buddhist background</source>
        <target>仏教徒としての背景</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Feats of inedia</source>
        <target>断食の偉業</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Reappearance in Ratanpur jungle</source>
        <target>ラタンプルのジャングルに再び現れる</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>New Appearance in 2009</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Sambodhi Dharma Sangha (earlier Palden Dorje, born Ram Bahadur Bomjan) was born on April 10, 1990 between 2:25am and 4am (information on date and time is still controversial and will be checked and clarified) in Ratanpur village, Bara district, Nepal.</source>
        <target>三菩提ダルマ・サンガ（前パルデン・ドルジェ、幼名ラム・バハドウール・ボムジャン）は1990年４月10日午前２時25分から４時の間に、ネパールのバラ地区ラタンプルで生まれました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Ram’s parents are farmers. His mother, Maya Devi was married at 12.  She had 5 sons and 4 daughters.  Ram was her third son.  When she was in her pregnancy, she found she was unable to eat meat without becoming ill.  The son, whom she named Ram, would not eat meat.  He would leave the house for long intervals from an early age.</source>
        <target>ラムの両親は百姓で、母親のマヤ・デヴィは１２歳で結婚し、５人の息子と４人の娘を授かりました。ラムは三男で、母親はラムを身ごもっていた時、肉を口にする度に気持ち悪くなってて食べられず、生まれて来た息子も肉を食べませんでした。ラムは幼い頃から度々家からいなくなることもありました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Ram was always pleased to see a lama or a holy person and fastidiously imitated them.  He often seemed to be lost in thought and spoke little.  Whenever someone spoke to him, he would reply with a smile and would treat people of all ages equally.</source>
        <target>ラムはいつもラマ僧や聖人が好きで、熱心にその人たちの真似をしていました。そして物思いにふけって、口数が少なくなることはしょっちゅうでした。誰かに話しかけられるといつも、微笑みを返し、どの年齢の人も同等に扱いました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>According to his family and neighbors, Ram Bomjan often acted differently from his childhood friends, frequently observing other people in worship and praying himself. He has been described as being born with a peaceful nature, and would never get into a fight or kill an animal. Beginning at the age of five he only took leftovers for food, and went hungry if there was nothing.</source>
        <target>ラム・ボムジャンの家族や近所の人の話しによると、小さい頃から他の子供達とは違ったふるまいをするのはしょっちゅうで、一人で拝んだり祈ったりして、他の人をよく観察していました。生まれつき平穏な性格で、喧嘩に入って行くこともなければ、動物を殺すこともなく、５歳の年から、飢えた人々に残した食べ物を持って行き始めました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He took his studies seriously and rarely played with other children, choosing instead to remain alone. He spent his time reading scriptures, meditating and worshipping the pipal tree which seemed to bring him joy. Seeing this behavior, Ram’s father sent him to study the scriptures of Lama Chhyoi with Samden Lama in their village.  After that Ram decided to embrace a religious life.</source>
        <target>真面目に勉学に励み、滅多に他の子供達と遊ぶことはなく、一人でいました。ラムは聖典を読んだり、瞑想したり、菩提樹を拝んだりし、それはラムに歓びを与えていたように見えました。息子のふるまいを見てラムの父親は自分の村のサムデン・ラマ僧のもとに息子を送り、ラマ・チョイの経典を勉強させた後、ラムは出家することにしました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He was accepted into the monkhood by Som Bahadur Lama of Sudha, Ward 8 of Chitwan Village Development Committee.</source>
        <target>そしてラムは、チトワン村自治体第８区スッダのソム・バハドウール・ラマ僧により、僧侶として受け入れられました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Som Bahadur Lama said the following of his ward: “He was obedient. He never said ‘no’ to my word. He was friendly and sociable and he received education in that manner. He used to say frequently that his attention was much more drawn towards meditation than towards reading books.”</source>
        <target>ソム・バハドウール・ラマ僧は次のように語っています。「ラムは従順で、私の言葉に決して『いいえ』と言いませんでした。人なつこく、人当たりもよく、そのようにして教育を受けました。そして自分自身よく言っていましたが、ラムの興味は本を読むことより、ずっと瞑想に傾いて行きました。」</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He was granted the initiation of</source>
        <target>ラムは</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Panchasheel</source>
        <target>五戒</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Panchasheel is a Sanskrit word for a Buddhist initiation consisting of five vows, which are as follows:</source>
        <target>の誓いをたてました。五戒（サンスクリット語で Panchasheel ）とは、仏門に帰依する時の次の五つの誓いのことです。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must not kill animals (it is preferable to be vegetarian)</source>
        <target>一、不殺生戒（ふせっしょうかい）： 生き物を殺さない。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must not steal</source>
        <target>二、不偸盗戒（ふちゅうとうかい）： 他人のものを盗まない。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must not lie</source>
        <target>三、不妄語戒（ふもうごかい） ： 嘘をつかない。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must refrain from sexual misconduct</source>
        <target>四、不邪淫戒（ふじゃいんかい) ； 自分の配偶者以外と交わらない。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must not take intoxicating substances</source>
        <target>五、不飲酒戒（ふおんじゅかい） ： 中毒性の物を飲まない。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Ram was initiated along with a group of nine other students. Ram refused to have his hair cut before the initiation, which was the common custom. It was after this initiation that Ram received the name,</source>
        <target>ラムは９人の弟子達と共に門下に入りましたが、一般的な慣習としての入門前に剃髪することをラムは拒みました。仏門伝授の後、ラムは</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje</source>
        <target>「パルデン・ドルジェ」</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>It was the custom for the initiates to meditate for up to a month in a cave. Som Bahadur Lama was surprised at the ease with which Palden Dorje seemed to adapt to the situation requiring little sustenance. It was then that he realized that the boy had a natural talent for deep and prolonged meditation.</source>
        <target>という名を受けました。洞窟で１ヶ月間瞑想することが仏門に入るための慣習 でしたが、パルデン・ドルジェが簡単にほとんど食べる物がない状態に適応しているのを見てソム・バハドウール・ラマ僧は驚き、この少年は深く持続する瞑想の才能を本来持っていることに気付いたのです。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>After completing his Buddhist education for two years, all nine initiates went to Lumbini, the birthplace of Lord Buddha, for sightseeing. Palden Dorje seemed utterly taken by this place and it seemed to deepen his religious resolve. The other eight initiates returned but he refused to return. Instead, he went to Dehradun to further his religious education with the Gurus of Dehradun. Later he returned to Nepal to the beautiful lakeside city of Pokhara.</source>
        <target>２年の仏教教育が完了し、９人全員で仏陀の生誕地であるルンビニを見物に出かけました。パルデン・ドルジェはすっかりこの地に心を奪われ、宗教的決心が強まったようでした。他の８人は戻りましたが、パルデン・ドルジェは帰りたがらず、デラドウンへ行き、そこの道師達から更に高い宗教教育を受けることにしました。後にパルデン・ドルジェはネパールの美しい湖畔の街ポカラに戻って来ました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Here it was that Palden Dorje became ill, and was unable to move his lower body.  Distressed, his teachers sent him home to recover.  During this time, Palden Dorje implored his family not to sacrifice any animals or take any alcohol otherwise further complications would arise.  He got better, but was still limping when he disappeared from his home the night of  May 16, 2005.</source>
        <target>そこでパルデン・ドルジェは病に伏せ、下半身を動かすことができなくなりました。悲嘆に暮れた導師達は、パルデン・ドルジェを療養のため家に帰すことにしました。その期間、パルデン・ドルジェは自分の家族に動物を殺して食べないよう、酒を飲まないよう、そしてもしそのような物をとったら、もっと大変な事が起きると嘆願しました。パルデン・ドルジェは元気になりましたが、2005年５月16日家を出た時はまだ足を引きずっていました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>When his mother became aware of the situation, she alerted the village, and everyone joined in the search for him.  A local boy claimed to have seen him while he was shaking a mango tree.  Palden Dorje had come up and picked up a mango, and stepped fully clothed into the river. “I thought you had disappeared,” – the boy remarked to Palden Dorje.</source>
        <target>母親がそれに気づき、村人たちに告げました。皆でいっしょにパルデン・ドルジェを探しまわっていると、地元の男の子がマンゴの木を揺すっている時、彼を見たと言いました。男の子の話しでは、パルデン・ドルジェがマンゴの木に登って実をとり、服を着たまま川の中に入って行くのを見て、「ぼく、お兄ちゃんが消えてどこかへ行ってしまったと思ったんだけど。」とパルデン・ドルジェに言うと「</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>“Have I?” – Palden Dorje  replied. – “You’d better go home, and be careful not to touch me.” The boy ran home to tell his story, but nobody believed him at first.  Palden Dorje’s relatives went to the ravine.  Palden Dorje smiled at them when they found him as was his habit.  They told him to come home.  “I’ll go home at four o’clock,” – Palden Dorje said.  His family decided it would be wise to keep an eye on him, and so some of his siblings stayed with him.</source>
        <target>ぼくが？」とパルデン・ドルジェは答え、「家に帰るんだ。ぼくに触らない方がいい。」と言いました。それから少年は走って家に帰りこの話しをしましたが、はじめは誰も信じてくれなかった、ということでした。パルデン・ドルジェの親戚は谷に行ってパルデン・ドルジェを見つけると、彼はいつもと同じように皆に微笑みました。親戚の人たちはパルデン・ドルジェに家に帰るよう言いましたが、パルデン・ドルジェは「４時に帰るよ。」と答えました。家族は絶対に息子から目を離さない方がいいと思い、兄弟の誰かがいつもいっしょにいることにしました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>At four o’clock, he picked up a couple of mangoes and began to eat one.  He told his little brother to bring him water, rice, his lama robes, a rosary and a picture of Buddha.  His little brother obeyed.  Palden Dorje’s sister came to tell Palden Dorje to come home at once.  Seeing how emaciated he looked from his previous  illness, she cried and begged him to come home.  Palden Dorje told her to stop crying, and she went home.</source>
        <target>４時になるとパルデン・ドルジェはマンゴをいくつか採って、そのうちの一つを食べ始め、弟に水と米、ラマ僧の袈裟、数珠、仏陀の絵を持って来させました。弟は言われたとおりにしました。姉が一度家に帰るように言いにやって来て、患っていた病気のため弟がやせ衰えているのを見、家に帰るよう泣いて頼みましたが、パルデン・ドルジェは姉に泣くのをやめて家に帰るようにと言いました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Then Palden Dorje, sitting in a meditative posture seemed to go into a trance.  He began to ask himself questions and answer them out loud. The other villagers came and told Palden Dorje to stop being silly and come home.</source>
        <target>それからパルデン・ドルジェは瞑想の姿勢で座り、トランスに入ったように見え、自分自身に質問し、大きな声でそれに答えるのです。村人たちもやって来て、そんな馬鹿げた事をしていないで家に帰るようパルデン・ドルジェに告げました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>They feared he must be ill or crazy.  When Palden Dorje’s older brother touched him, Palden Dorje’s body became exceedingly hot and turned red. “Please leave me alone, or one of us may die,” – Palden Dorje said. – “If anyone disturbs me or my things at midnight, I will have to meditate for 20 years, but if all goes well, I will meditate for 6 years.”</source>
        <target>村人たちはパルデン・ドルジェは病気になったか、気が狂ってしまったに違いないと心配になりました。パルデン・ドルジェの兄が彼に触ると、体は非常に熱くなり、そして赤くなりました。「どうかぼくを一人にして。でないと、ぼくらのうちの誰か一人は死んでしまうから。もし夜中に誰かが、ぼくやぼくの物を邪魔したら、２０年間瞑想せねばならない。でも、すべてがうまく行けば６年間の瞑想で終わる。」とパルデン・ドルジェは言いました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Then Palden Dorje, followed by his brother, and at a distance by the villagers set out to find a good meditation  place in the forest. His parents insisted he take some food and water with him.  Finally, he reached his destination  at 11:00 AM on May 18, 2005. This was the day the villagers of Ratanpur celebrated</source>
        <target>その後パルデン・ドルジェは人里離れた森の中、瞑想によい場所を探しに行き、そして兄は彼について行ったのです。両親は絶対に何か食べ物と飲み物を持って行くよう言いました。2005年５月18日午前11時とうとう目的地に着きました。その日はラタンプルの村で仏教の</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vesak</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Buddha Jayanti (Vesak)</source>
        <target>ウェーサーカ祭</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He settled himself under a pipal tree, having offered 10 kinds of fruit to the picture of Buddha.</source>
        <target>のお祝いがあった日でした。パルデン・ドルジェは菩提樹の下に座ると、仏陀の絵に１０種類の果物を捧げました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>About 30 villagers saw where Palden Dorje was meditating, and they left an offering of over a thousand rupees as was the custom at Buddha Jayanti.  On that night at 12:00,  some pranksters came to disturb Palden Dorje and steal the offering.  They quarreled over the money, and later accused each other in front of the villagers.  Having confessed, they asked Palden Dorje’s forgiveness.</source>
        <target>およそ３０人の村人がパルデン・ドルジェが瞑想している所を目撃し、ウェーサーカ祭の慣習である布施を1000ルピー以上捧げて行きました。その夜１２時、心ない者たちがパルデン・ドルジェの邪魔をしにやって来て、お供えを盗んで行きました。その者たちはお金を巡って喧嘩となり、村人たちの前で責め合い、とうとう自分達の罪を認め、パルデン・ドルジェに許しを請いました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>So Palden Dorje left the first meditation place and went north on the 24th of May, 2005.  At that time he gave six pipal leaves to his second elder brother telling him to keep them in oil.  He said that as long as his family kept the leaves, all would be well.  His relatives cried when he left.</source>
        <target>そうして2005年５月24日、パルデン・ドルジェは初めの瞑想の地を去り、北に向かいました。その時パルデン・ドルジェは２番目の兄に菩提樹の葉を６枚渡し、それを油に浸けておくよう言いました。家族がその葉を持っている限りすべてうまく行くと告げて去り、残された親戚たちは涙を流しました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Again the villagers were concerned about Palden Dorje’s whereabouts, and in the late afternoon, a cowherd had seen him in his new meditation site. The villagers sent some of his family to go and bring him home.  But Palden Dorje refused and  moved to another pipal tree in the east.</source>
        <target>村人たちはまたパルデン・ドルジェがどこにいるのか心配していると、午後遅く牛飼いが新しい瞑想の場所に彼がいるのを見たのでした。村人がパルデン・ドルジェの家族に言って彼を家に連れて帰らせよようとしましたが、パルデン・ドルジェはそれを拒み、東の方角にある別の菩提樹に移りました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje told his family that he must continue to meditate at all costs.  He drew a boundary around his meditation area, and the villagers and his relatives built a fence for him. More and more crowds gathered at the site, so Palden Dorje ordered that a hut be built and sealed with plastic on all sides wherein he remained for 15 days. After that Palden Dorje said, “I have received some energy so that I may now meditate under a tree outside”.</source>
        <target>パルデン・ドルジェは家族に何としてでも瞑想を続けねばならないと告げ、自分が瞑想する範囲に境界線を書き、村人と親戚がパルデン・ドルジェのために柵を立てました。更に多くの人々が彼を一目見ようと集まって来たため、パルデン・ドルジェは庵を造らせ、その周りをビニールで覆い、その中で１５日間瞑想しました。その後パルデン・ドルジェは「ある程度エネルギーを受け取ったので、今から外の樹の下で瞑想します。」と言いました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>There was a terrible drought in the village. Palden Dorje told them to pray to a snake god and after 5 days, it started raining. In the 75th day of meditation, he opened the eyes and asked his elder brother to call him by the words: “Om Namó Gurú Búddha Gyáni”.</source>
        <target>村ではひどい日照りが続いており、パルデン・ドルジェは村人に蛇神に祈るよう告げました。するとその５日後に雨が降り始めました。瞑想の７５日目、パルデン・ドルジェは目を開け、兄に「オム・ナモ・グル・ブッダ・ギャーニ」と呼ぶようにと言うと、瞑想に戻りました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He returned to his meditation. Since that day he was addressed as</source>
        <target>その日からパルデン・ドルジェは</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>“Om Namo Guru Buddha Gyani”</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>(Hail to the Master of the Wisdom of Buddha.)</source>
        <target>（仏陀の英知に達した者に栄光あれ）と呼ばれるようになりました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On August 18, 2005, Palden Dorje called together his friends who were lamas.  They asked him how it was that Palden Dorje was surviving without water. Palden Dorje replied that two snake gods protected him from either side.  That day Palden Dorje also changed his clothes and wore a white cloth called Ngag.</source>
        <target>2005年８月18日パルデン・ドルジェは自分と同期にラマ僧であった友人たちを呼びました。どうやってパルデン・ドルジェが水なしで生きていられるのかと彼らが尋ねると、パルデン・ドルジェは両側から２体の蛇神が守ってくれているのだと答えました。その日パルデン・ドルジェも服を着替え、ナガ（蛇）と呼ばれる白い衣を身にまといました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On November 6, 2005 snake bit Palden Dorje, and Palden Dorje’s body was poisoned. Palden Dorje sweated more than two liters while he continued to meditate, and thus he overcame the poison.  Palden Dorje’s followers believe that on that day he was enlightened, for the Bodhisattva has the ability to survive attached to a tree, soil and stone, to digest snake poison, to be unaffected by the wind and to understand the language of all creatures.</source>
        <target>2005年11月６日パルデン・ドルジェは蛇に咬まれ体に毒が回り、瞑想を続ける中２リットル以上汗をかき、そのようにして排毒しました。パルデン・ドルジェの信奉者たちはその日パルデン・ドルジェは悟りを開いたと信じます。というのが菩薩は木や土、石と一体になったり、蛇の毒を消したり、風に影響されなかったり、生き物の言葉がわかることで生き残る能力があるからです。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On November 8, 2005, Palden Dorje told the people that he did not have the energy of a Buddha, and he asked them not to publicize him as an incarnation of Buddha.</source>
        <target>2005年11月８日パルデン・ドルジェは人々に、自分は仏陀のようなエネルギーは持っておらず、自分を仏陀の生まれ変わりだと宣伝するのはやめるようにと頼みました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On November 11, 2005 a bright light appeared shining from Palden Dorje’s head.  His followers cried with joy and became even more fervent.</source>
        <target>2005年11月11日パルデン・ドルジェの頭からまばゆい光が現れ、信奉者たちは歓びで涙を流し、更に熱狂的になりました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>“Leave me in peace, and there will soon be peace in the country,” – Palden Dorje said. However crowds ever increased and people chanted and set up a market place, according to Radio HBC 94 FM who visited the site on December 10, 2005. The crowds were kept at a distance of about 50 meters. All witnesses claimed that Palden Dorje neither ate, drank or left to relieve himself.  He just sat and meditated under the pipal tree. Baffled onlookers were ever increasing.</source>
        <target>「私をそっとしておいてください、そうすればまもなくこの国に平和が訪れるでしょう。」とパルデン・ドルジェは言いました。しかし群衆は更に増え、人々は祈りを唱え、店までできてしまい、2005年12月10日その場所を訪れたラジオHBC94FMによると群衆の列は５０メートルにも及んだと言います。目撃者は皆、パルデン・ドルジェは飲みもしないし食べもせず休憩もせず、ただ菩提樹の下で座って瞑想をしていたと言っています。びっくりした見物人は更に増えていきました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>There were stories of miracles: a</source>
        <target>数々の奇跡が起き、発声障害のあった</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>girl</source>
        <target>少女</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>and a young man had gained the power of speech although they could not speak.</source>
        <target>と若い男性が 話せるようにもなりました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>After about ten months of meditation, Palden Dorje went missing on 11 March 2006. He gave no explanation, and some believed he had been abducted. His followers theorized that he went deeper into the woods to look for a quieter place to meditate.</source>
        <target>2006年３月11日、約10ヶ月の瞑想の後、パルデン・ドルジェがいなくなりました。全く説明もなかったので、誘拐されたのではと思った人もいました。信奉者たちは、パルデン・ドルジェは瞑想のためもっと静かな場所を探しに、更に森の中深くまで行ったのだろうと考えました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Police abandoned a search for him after the possibility of foul play was eliminated. Suspecting money laundering, the authorities froze the bank account of the local committee managing the crowds, which had gathered more than Rs. 600,000 ($7950), but they found no evidence.</source>
        <target>犯罪が却下された可能性のため警察がパルデン・ドルジェの捜索をとりやめました。疑惑金が偽装されたということで、Rs. 600,000 ($7950)ルピー以上集められた地元の委員会の銀行口座が凍結されましたが、証拠は見つかりませんでした。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 19 March, a group of Palden Dorje's followers met with him about 2 miles (3 kilometers) southwest of his meditation site. They say they spoke to him for thirty minutes, during which Palden Dorje said: "There is no peace here" and that he would return in six years, which would be in 2011 or 2012. He left a message for his parents telling them not to worry.</source>
        <target>３月19日パルデン・ドルジェの信奉者のグループが先の瞑想場所から南西約３kmのあたりでパルデン・ドルジェに出会い、そこで３０分話したということです。パルデン・ドルジェは「ここには平安がない。」と告げ、６年後に戻ると言い残しました。つまりそれは2011年か2012年ということです。また両親には心配しないよう伝えてくれと頼みました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 25 December 2006, villagers in Bara district spotted Palden Dorje meditating. He was carrying a sword for protection in the jungle, reminding reporters that "Even Gautama Buddha had to protect himself," and claimed to have eaten nothing but herbs in the interim.</source>
        <target>2006年12月25日バラ地区の村人がパルデン・ドルジェを見つけました。パルデン・ドルジェはジャングルで身を守るため刀を携えていたことは、「ゴータマ仏陀さえ自分の身を守らねばならなかった。」ことを思い起こさせます。彼はしばらくの間薬草を食べた後は、何も食べていませんでした。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He reiterated his six year commitment to Buddhist devotion, and said he would allow people to come and observe him, as long as they remained at some distance and didn't bother him. When a reporter pointed out that pilgrims to his meditation site would be making donations in his name, he asked for the donations to not be abused or used for commercial purposes. A new wave of visitors came to see him and pray at his new meditation spot. On 8 March 2007 he left Bara district to again find a quieter place to meditate.</source>
        <target>パルデン・ドルジェは仏門帰依への６年の公約を何度も繰り返し、少し離れていて邪魔をしないのであれば、ここに来て自分を傍観してもいいと言いました。巡礼者たちが彼の瞑想を拝みにやって来る時、彼の名のもと布施をするのではと指摘すると、パルデン・ドルジェはその布施を悪用してはいけないし、広告の目的にも使わないようにと頼みました。新しい瞑想地に新しい訪問者の波がパルデン・ドルジェを一目拝みたいとおしよせて来ました。2007年３月８日パルデン・ドルジェは瞑想のため、再びもっと静かな場所を探すためバラ地区を離れたのでした。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 26 March 2007, Inspector Rameshwor Yadav of the Area Police Post Nijgadh, found Palden Dorje inside a bunker-like ditch seven feet square. A police team under Yadav's command had gone to the place after word had spread of Palden Dorje meditating underground. “His face was clean and hair was combed well,” – Yadav said.</source>
        <target>2007年３月26日ニジュガード区域警察のラメシュヴォル・ヤダヴ検査官が、四角い約２m10cmの石炭入れのような箱の中にいるパルデン・ドルジェを発見し、「パルデン・ドルジェが地下で瞑想」という言葉が広まり、ヤダヴの命令のもと警察部隊がその場所に行きました。「その顔は清潔で髪も櫛でとかしてあった。」とヤダヴは言っています。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>According to him, the bunker had been cemented from all sides and fitted with a tiled roof. Indra Lama, a local deployed as Palden Dorje's caretaker since the beginning of his intensive meditation, said the bunker was prepared per Palden Dorje's request. “After granting audience a week ago, he expressed his desire to meditate inside the ground; so we built it,” – he said.</source>
        <target>ヤダヴによるとその大箱は四方がセメントで固めてあり、タイルの屋根がはめ込んであったということです。インドラ・ラマ僧はパルデン・ドルジェが集中的な瞑想のはじまりから世話人として配置されてきており、箱はパルデン・ドルジェの要望で準備されたと言っています。 「一週間前に拝観を許してから、地下で瞑想をしたいと言われ、我々はそれを作った。」と語りました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 2 August 2007, Palden Dorje</source>
        <target>2007年８月２日パルデン・ドルジェはネパール南部のバラ地区のハルコーリアのジャングルで</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>addressed a large crowd</source>
        <target>大衆を前に説教を</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>in Halkhoriya jungle in Bara district of southern Nepal. The Namo Buddha Tapoban Committee, which is devoted to looking after Palden Dorje, assembled the meeting.</source>
        <target>し、パルデン・ドルジェを献身的に見守って来たナモ・ブッダ・タポバン委員会はその会を招集しました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>A notice about the boy's first-ever preaching was broadcast by a local FM radio station, and the committee also invited people by telephone. Around three thousand people gathered to listen to Palden Dorje's address. A video was made of the event. According to Upendra Lamichhane, a blogger who wrote an article and took pictures of the meeting, Palden Dorje's message was, "The only way we can save this nation is through spirituality".</source>
        <target>その少年の初めての説教は地元のFMラジオ局によって放送され、委員会は電話で人々を招待しました。約三千人の人々がパルデン・ドルジェの話しを聞こうと集まり、映像も映されれました。その会合の記事を書き写真を撮ったブログ作家のウペンドラ・ラミチャネによると、パルデン・ドルジェのメッセージは「この国を救うことができるただ一つの道は霊性を通じてのみである。」ということでした。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>This was his speech:</source>
        <target>以下が仏陀少年による講話です。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje is a member of the</source>
        <target>パルデン・ドルジェは、</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Tamang</source>
        <target>タマン族</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>community, of which a majority practices</source>
        <target>共同体の一員で、彼らは主に</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Vajrayana Buddhism</source>
        <target>金剛乗仏教に従っています。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje's story gained popularity because it resembled a legend from the Jataka Nidanakatha about</source>
        <target>パルデン・ドルジェの話はジャータカ物語にある</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Gautama Buddha's</source>
        <target>ゴータマ仏陀が</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>enlightenment, so much so that some devotees claimed Palden Dorje was the reincarnation of a Buddha.</source>
        <target>悟る時の話とたいへん似ていることから、どんどん人に知られるようになり、パルデン・ドルジェは仏陀の生まれ変わりだという帰依者もいます。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>However, on 8 November 2005 Dorje arose and said: “Tell the people not to call me a Buddha. I don't have the Buddha's energy. I am at the level of a rimpoche.” A rimpoche is a teacher, which indicates he believes he has achieved a significant amount. He said that he will need six more years of meditation before he may become a Buddha.</source>
        <target>しかし、2005年11月８日パルデン・ドルジェははっきりと、「私を仏陀と呼ばないように人々に言いなさい。私は仏陀のエネルギーを持っていません。私はリンポチェの段階です。」と言いました。リンポチェとは 重要な位に達したと示される導師のことです。パルデン・ドルジェは自分が仏陀になるため、あと６年の瞑想が必要だと語りました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>According to his followers, Palden Dorje may have reached the stage of a</source>
        <target>信奉者によると、おそらくパルデン・ドルジェは</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Bodhisattva </source>
        <target>菩薩</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>a person on the path to attaining full enlightenment or buddhahood for the benefit of all sentient beings. According to the historical Buddha, Gautama Buddha, there were innumerable Buddhas before him and infinite Buddhas to come. Proponents also claim that Palden Dorje might also be</source>
        <target>の段階、すなわち衆生すべてのために完全なる悟りを開く、または仏性に達する前の段階に達したのではないか、ということです。歴史上の釈迦、ゴータマ仏陀は、自分より前に無数の仏が存在した、そして無限の仏がやって来ると言いました。支持者たちはパルデン・ドルジェが、歴史上の仏陀が予言した後継者である</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Maitreya</source>
        <target>弥勒菩薩</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Bodhisattva, the predicted successor to the historical Buddha.</source>
        <target>であるかもしれないとも言っています。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>His mother's name is Maya Devi Tamang, the same first name as Buddha's mother. It is reported that his mother fainted when she found out that her son intended to meditate for an indefinite period.</source>
        <target>パルデン・ドルジェの母親の名は釈尊の母親と同じマヤ・デヴィ・タマンといい、いつ終わるかわからない期間、自分の息子が瞑想しようとしているのを知って、気絶してしまったそうです。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Those who have called him the "reincarnation of Buddha" have been criticised. Gautama Buddha taught that after</source>
        <target>パルデン・ドルジェを「仏陀の生まれ変わり」と呼んだ人々は批判を受けました。ゴータマ仏陀は</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>parinirvana</source>
        <target>般涅槃</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>there is no more rebirth, therefore it is impossible to be a "reincarnation of Buddha", but it is possible to be another Buddha, another who has attained, or will attain, enlightenment.</source>
        <target>の後もはや生まれ変わる事はないと教えたので「仏陀の生まれ変わり」というのはおかしいと。しかし、悟りに達した、または達しようとしている他の仏陀でありえるのではないでしょうか。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>An average human being who stops drinking will die of dehydration in three to four days. According to the Guinness Book of Records the longest time a human has survived without water is 18 days. Palden Dorje, on the other hand, does not appear to break his meditation to eat or drink.</source>
        <target>普通の人間は何も飲まないでいると３、４日で脱水症状となり死んでしまいます。ギネス・ブックによると、水なしで１８日間生き延びた人が最長記録です。一方パルデン・ドルジェは食べたり飲んだりするために瞑想を途中で休む事は全くありません。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje was observed not to leave the tree at least during the daytime, but nobody was allowed to approach him too closely. Between 5:00 p.m. and 5:00 a.m. nobody was allowed to see him, and a screen was erected for that purpose. Many people speculated that he ate and drank water during that time.</source>
        <target>パルデン・ドルジェは少なくとも昼間、樹から離れたところを目撃した人はいませんし、また誰も彼に近づきすぎてもいけません。午後５時から午前５時の間、誰もパルデン・ドルジェを見てはならず、そのため幕が掛けられており、その時に食べたり飲んだりしているんではないか、と疑っている人も少なくありません。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Some supporters believe that discussions of</source>
        <target> </target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inedia</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>inedia</source>
        <target>断食</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>are irrelevant, and that the ability to sit nearly motionless in the same position day after day, with no regard for extremes of weather including a cold winter and a monsoon season, is notable. For example, American writer George Saunders visited Palden Dorje and observed him through a single night, and was impressed by Palden Dorje's perfectly still stature, even during an evening climate that seemed unbearably cold to the much better clothed journalist.</source>
        <target>についての議論は無意味であって、どんなに寒い冬でもモンスーン期でもひどい天気に関係なく、何日も同じ姿勢でほとんど動かず座れることが注目に値すると信じる人々がいます。たとえば、アメリカ人作家のジョージ・ソンダースがパルデン・ドルジェを訪れた時、一晩中彼を観察していましたが、夕方ジャケットを着なければならないほど寒くなっても、じっと静かに座っているパルデン・ドルジェに感動したと言っています。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>In December 2005, a nine-member government committee led by Gunjaman Lama watched Palden Dorje carefully for 48 hours and observed him not to take any food or water during that time. A video recording was also made of this test. However, they were unable to approach closer than 3 meters or take readings of his vital signs. The Nepalese government planned a more careful scientific study, but the plan was never carried out.</source>
        <target>2005年12月グンジャマン・ラマ僧に案内され９人の政府関係者がパルデン・ドルジェを見に来ました。その時は48時間パルデン・ドルジェが食べ物も水も採らない事が注意深く観察されました。このテストではビデオでも記録されました。しかしながら、３m以内には近づけず、生命 反応も取れなかったので、ネパール政府は更に注意深い科学的調査を計画したのですが、まだ実行されていません。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>In 2007, the Discovery Channel produced a documentary titled</source>
        <target>2007年ディスカバリーチャンネルが「</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>The Boy With Divine Powers</source>
        <target>仏性を持つ少年</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On their first, four-day attempt, the film crew was required to stay outside a guarded barbed-wire fence, and their camera's infrared capabilities did not pick up evidence of a body at the base of the tree where Palden Dorje sat during their non-stop recording. On a second attempt a few weeks later, however, the film crew was able to film Palden Dorje continuously for 96 hours, day and night, during which time he did not drink any fluids or eat any food. According to scientists on the documentary, an average person would be expected to die from kidney failure after four days without drinking any fluids. The boy showed no signs of classical physical deterioration caused by dehydration. A close inspection by the film crew of the area around the tree where Palden Dorje was sitting revealed no hidden food supply or water pipes.</source>
        <target>」というタイトルのドキュメンタリーを制作しました。はじめの４日間の試みでは針金の柵の外に制作スタッフはいなければならず、ノンストップで記録を撮る間、カメラの赤外線能力はパルデン・ドルジェが座っている樹のつけ根の部分に体の形跡をつかむことができませんでした。しかし数週間後、２度目の試みで制作スタッフは、パルデン・ドルジェを昼夜96時間継続して映すことができ、その間パルデン・ドルジェは何の液体も食べ物もとっていませんでした。ドキュメンタリーに出演した科学者によると、普通ヒトは何も飲まなければ４日後腎臓不全により死んでしまう、ということです。この少年は脱水症状によって身体レベルが悪化した形跡もありませんでした。制作スタッフがパルデン・ドルジェの 座っている樹の周りを綿密に調べましたが、食べ物も水道管も全く隠されていませんでした。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 10 November 2008, Palden Dorje</source>
        <target>2008年11月10日カトマンズーの南東150kmニジュガードの近くラタンプールの人里離れたジャングルに、パルデン・ドルジェは帰依者のグループの前に再び</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>reappeared and spoke</source>
        <target>現れ話をしました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>to a group of devotees in the remote jungle of Ratanpur, 150 km (95 miles) southeast of Kathmandu, near Nijgadh. His hair was shoulder-length and his body was wrapped in a white cloth.</source>
        <target>髪は肩までのび、体は白い衣に包まれていました。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>His devotees believe he attained enlightenment at Bodh Gaya in Bihar, which borders Nepal – the place where Siddartha Gautama attained enlightenment.</source>
        <target>ゴ－タマ・シッダールタが悟りに達した場所である、ネパールとの国境に近いインドのビハール州ブッダガヤで、パルデン・ドルジェは悟りを開くのではないかと信奉者たちは思っています。</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>biography_translated_by</source>
        <target>Ehko Merlo</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
<!-- утф -->
    </body>
  </file>
</xliff>