<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<xliff version="1.0">
  <file original="global" source-language="en" datatype="plaintext">
    <body>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Dharma Sangha - Biography - eTapasvi.com</source>
        <target>Dharma Sangha - Biographie - eTapasvi.com</target>
      </trans-unit>

<!-- showSuccess -->
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Family and Childhood</source>
        <target>Famille et Enfance</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>School and Religious Education</source>
        <target>Éducation scolaire et religieuse</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje's Illness</source>
        <target>Maladie</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje Disappears</source>
        <target>Palden Dorje disparaît</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Meditation Begins</source>
        <target>Débuts de la méditation</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Snakebite and Miracles</source>
        <target>Sheshha Naga et la Morsure du Serpent</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Wandering to Bara district</source>
        <target>Errance dans la région de Bara</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Meditating in pit</source>
        <target>Méditation sous terre</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Preaching in Halkoriya jungle</source>
        <target>Sermon dans la jungle d'Halkhoria</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Buddhist background</source>
        <target>Contexte bouddhiste</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Feats of inedia</source>
        <target>Exploits d'inédie (jeûne)</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Reappearance in Ratanpuri jungle</source>
        <target>Réapparition dans la jungle de Ratanpuri</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>New Appearance in 2009</source>
        <target>Nouvelle apparition en 2009</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Dharma Sangha (earlier Palden Dorje, born Ram Bahadur Bomjan) was born on April 9, 1990 in Ratanpuri village, Bara district, Nepal.</source>
        <target>Ram Bahadur Bonjam, aussi connu sous son nom de moine bouddhiste Palden Dorje, est né le 9 avril 1990, au village de Ratanpuri, district de Bara, au Népal.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Ram’s parents are farmers. His mother, Maya Devi was married at 12.  She had 5 sons and 4 daughters.  Ram was her third son.  When she was in her pregnancy, she found she was unable to eat meat without becoming ill.  The son, whom she named Ram, would not eat meat.  He would leave the house for long intervals from an early age.</source>
        <target>Les parents de Ram sont agriculteurs. Sa mère, Maya Devi, s’est mariée à l’âge de 12 ans. Elle a donné naissance à 5 garçons et 4 filles. Ram est son troisième fils. Quand elle était enceinte, elle était incapable de manger de la viande sans devenir malade. Son fils, qu’elle prénomma Ram, n’a d’ailleurs jamais mangé de viande.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Ram was always pleased to see a lama or a holy person and fastidiously imitated them.  He often seemed to be lost in thought and spoke little.  Whenever someone spoke to him, he would reply with a smile and would treat people of all ages equally.</source>
        <target>Dès son jeune âge, Ram observait toujours avec beaucoup d’intérêt les lamas ou personnes saintes et rapidement se mit à les imiter méticuleusement. Souvent, il semblait perdu dans ses pensées et parlait peu. Lorsqu’une personne lui adressait la parole, il répondait généralement par un sourire et gardait la même attitude vis-à-vis des individus de tous âges. Il avait aussi l’habitude de se retirer seul pendant de longues périodes.</target>
      </trans-unit>
  
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>According to his family and neighbors, Ram Bomjan often acted differently from his childhood friends, frequently observing other people in worship and praying himself. He has been described as being born with a peaceful nature, and would never get into a fight or kill an animal. Beginning at the age of five he only took leftovers for food, and went hungry if there was nothing.</source>
        <target>Selon sa famille et ses voisins, Ram agissait tout à fait différemment des autres enfants de son âge. Il se plaisait à regarder les autres gens pendant leurs activités d’adoration et s’adonnait lui-même à la prière. Sa famille le décrit comme étant d’une nature calme et paisible. Il ne se mêlait jamais aux disputes ou aux batailles et refusait qu’on tue un animal. À partir de l’âge de 5 ans, il n’acceptait de manger que les restes de sa famille et demeurait sur sa faim s’il ne restait plus rien.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He took his studies seriously and rarely played with other children, choosing instead to remain alone. He spent his time reading scriptures, meditating and worshipping the pipal tree which seemed to bring him joy. Seeing this behavior, Ram’s father sent him to study the scriptures of Lama Chhyoi with Samden Lama in their village.  After that Ram decided to embrace a religious life.</source>
        <target>Ram prenait ses études au sérieux et jouait rarement avec ses pairs, préférant la solitude. Il consacrait son temps à lire des textes sacrés, à méditer et à vénérer un arbre figuier, ce qui semblait lui apporter beaucoup de joie. Constatant un tel comportement, le père de Ram l’envoya étudier les écrits sacrés de Lama Chhyoi avec Lama Samden dans leur village. Ram décida ensuite d’embrasser une vie religieuse.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He was accepted into the monkhood by Som Bahadur Lama of Sudha, Ward 8 of Chitwan Village Development Committee.</source>
        <target>Il a été accepté dans la vie monastique par Som Bahadur Lama de Sudha, Ward 8 de Chitwan Village Comité du développement.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Som Bahadur Lama said the following of his ward: “He was obedient. He never said ‘no’ to my word. He was friendly and sociable and he received education in that manner. He used to say frequently that his attention was much more drawn towards meditation than towards reading books.”</source>
        <target>Le Lama Som Bahadur dit ceci concernant Ram: « Il était obéissant. Il ne disait jamais non à ce que je lui demandais. Il était amical et sociable et reçut une éducation qui allait dans ce sens. Il disait fréquemment que son attention était bien plus portée à la méditation qu'à lire des livres. »</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He was granted the initiation of</source>
        <target>Ram reçut l'initiation de</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Panchasheel</source>
        <target>Panchasheel</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Panchasheel is a Sanskrit word for a Buddhist initiation consisting of five vows, which are as follows:</source>
        <target>Les cinq voeux sont les suivants:</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must not kill animals (it is preferable to be vegetarian)</source>
        <target>Ne pas tuer d'animaux (il est préférable d'être végétarien)</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must not steal</source>
        <target>Ne pas voler</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must not lie</source>
        <target>Ne pas mentir</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must refrain from sexual misconduct</source>
        <target>Ne pas penser négativement concernant d'autres personnes</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must not take intoxicating substances</source>
        <target>Ne pas consommer de substances intoxicantes.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Ram was initiated along with a group of nine other students. Ram refused to have his hair cut before the initiation, which was the common custom. It was after this initiation that Ram received the name,</source>
        <target>Ram a été initié en même temps que neuf autres étudiants. Ram refusa de se faire couper les cheveux avant l'initiation, ce qui était pourtant la coutume. C'est après cette initiation qu'il reçut le nom de</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje</source>
        <target>Palden Dorje</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>It was the custom for the initiates to meditate for up to a month in a cave. Som Bahadur Lama was surprised at the ease with which Palden Dorje seemed to adapt to the situation requiring little sustenance. It was then that he realized that the boy had a natural talent for deep and prolonged meditation.</source>
        <target>Après cette initiation, il était coutume pour les initiés de méditer pendant un mois ou plus dans une cave. Som Bahadur Lama dit avoir été surpris de voir avec quelle aisance Palden Dorje s'adapta à cette nouvelle expérience, ne nécessitant que très peu de nourriture. C'est à ce moment-là qu'il réalisa que l'enfant avait un don pour les méditations prolongées.</target>
	  </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>After completing his Buddhist education for two years, all nine initiates went to Lumbini, the birthplace of Lord Buddha, for sightseeing. Palden Dorje seemed utterly taken by this place and it seemed to deepen his religious resolve. The other eight initiates returned but he refused to return. Instead, he went to Dehradun to further his religious education with the Gurus of Dehradun. Later he returned to Nepal to the beautiful lakeside city of Pokhara.</source>
        <target>Après avoir achevé leurs études bouddhiques de deux années, les neufs initiés se rendirent à Lumbini, le lieu de naissance du Seigneur Bouddha. Palden Dorje fut apparemment fasciné par cet endroit, ce qui eut pour effet de fortifier ses convictions spirituelles. Les huit autres initiés retournèrent d'où ils venaient mais Palden Dorje refusa. Il préféra aller à Dheradun afin de parfaire ses études religieuses. Il retourna ensuite à la magnifique ville côtière de Pokhara.</target>
	  </trans-unit>  

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Here it was that Palden Dorje became ill, and was unable to move his lower body.  Distressed, his teachers sent him home to recover.  During this time, Palden Dorje implored his family not to sacrifice any animals or take any alcohol otherwise further complications would arise.  He got better, but was still limping when he disappeared from his home the night of  May 16, 2005.</source>
        <target>C'est à cette période que Palden Dorje devint malade, il était incapable de bouger la partie inférieure de son corps. Bouleversés, ses enseignants l'envoyèrent chez lui pour récupérer. Durant cette période, Palden Dorje implora sa famille de ne pas sacrifier d'animaux et de ne pas boire d'alcool, autrement la situation pourrait s'aggraver. Son état de santé s'améliora mais il était encore boiteux au moment où il disparût de sa maison la nuit du 16 Mai 2005.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>When his mother became aware of the situation, she alerted the village, and everyone joined in the search for him.  A local boy claimed to have seen him while he was shaking a mango tree.  Palden Dorje had come up and picked up a mango, and stepped fully clothed into the river. “I thought you had disappeared,” – the boy remarked to Palden Dorje.</source>
        <target>Lorsque sa mère se rendit compte de la situation, elle alerta le village et tout le monde se joignit à sa recherche. Un garçon des environs affirma l'avoir vu pendant qu'il était en train de secouer un manguier. Palden Dorje l'aurait rejoint, aurait pris une mangue, et ensuite aurait marché habillé dans la rivière. Le garçon lui dit alors “Je pensais que tu avais disparu?”.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>“Have I?” – Palden Dorje  replied. – “You’d better go home, and be careful not to touch me.” The boy ran home to tell his story, but nobody believed him at first.  Palden Dorje’s relatives went to the ravine.  Palden Dorje smiled at them when they found him as was his habit.  They told him to come home.  “I’ll go home at four o’clock,” – Palden Dorje said.  His family decided it would be wise to keep an eye on him, and so some of his siblings stayed with him.</source>
        <target> “Vraiment?” lui répondit Palden Dorje. “Tu ferais mieux de rentrer à ta maison et sois prudent de ne pas me toucher.” Le garçon courut jusqu'à sa maison et raconta son histoire, mais dans un premier temps, personne ne voulut le croire. Les proches de Palden Dorje (Guru) allèrent tout de même jusqu'au ravin. Quand ils le trouvèrent, Palden Dorje leur souri comme à son habitude. Ils lui demandèrent de rentrer à la maison. “Je serai à la maison à 4 heures.” leur dit Guru. Sa famille décida qu'il était plus sage que quelques-uns de ces frères et soeurs restent avec lui.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>At four o’clock, he picked up a couple of mangoes and began to eat one.  He told his little brother to bring him water, rice, his lama robes, a rosary and a picture of Buddha.  His little brother obeyed.  Palden Dorje’s sister came to tell Palden Dorje to come home at once.  Seeing how emaciated he looked from his previous  illness, she cried and begged him to come home.  Palden Dorje told her to stop crying, and she went home.</source>
        <target>Quand vint 4 heures, il prit à nouveau quelques mangues et commença à en manger une. Il demanda à son petit frère de lui apporter de l'eau, du riz, sa robe de lama, un rosaire et une image du Bouddha. Son petit frère obéit. Une de ses soeurs alla le chercher afin qu'il rentre une bonne fois pour toute. En voyant dans quel état il était après sa maladie, elle pleura et le supplia de rentrer à la maison. Guru lui demanda d'arrêter de pleurer, après quoi elle retourna chez elle.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Then Palden Dorje, sitting in a meditative posture seemed to go into a trance.  He began to ask himself questions and answer them out loud. The other villagers came and told Palden Dorje to stop being silly and come home.</source>
        <target>C'est alors que Palden Dorje, assis dans une posture de méditation, sembla entrer en transe. Il commença à se poser des questions et y répondait à haute voix. Les autres villageois vinrent le trouver et lui demandèrent d'arrêter de faire l'idiot.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>They feared he must be ill or crazy.  When Palden Dorje’s older brother touched him, Palden Dorje’s body became exceedingly hot and turned red. “Please leave me alone, or one of us may die,” – Palden Dorje said. – “If anyone disturbs me or my things at midnight, I will have to meditate for 20 years, but if all goes well, I will meditate for 6 years.”</source>
        <target>Ils craignaient qu'il soit devenu fou ou malade. Quand son frère aîné le toucha, le corps de Guru devint extrêmement chaud et rouge. “S'il te plaît, laisse-moi seul, ou l'un de nous deux pourrait mourir.” dit Palden Dorje. “Si je continue à être dérangé après minuit, j'aurai besoin de méditer pendant 20 ans, mais si tout se passe bien, je méditerai pendant 6 ans.”</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Then Palden Dorje, followed by his brother, and at a distance by the villagers set out to find a good meditation  place in the forest. His parents insisted he take some food and water with him.  Finally, he reached his destination  at 11:00 AM on May 18, 2005. This was the day the villagers of Ratanpuri celebrated</source>
        <target>Ensuite Guru, suivi par son frère et à une certaine distance par les villageois, chercha un bon endroit dans la forêt pour commencer sa méditation. Finalement, il atteignit sa destination à 11h du matin le 18 Mai 2005. Ce même jour, les villageois de Ratanpuri célébrèrent la</target>
      </trans-unit>      

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vesak</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Buddha Jayanti (Vesak)</source>
        <target>Buddha Jayanti (Vésak)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He settled himself under a pipal tree, having offered 10 kinds of fruit to the picture of Buddha.</source>
        <target>Palden Dorje s'installa sous un arbre figuier, et offrit dix fruits différents à l'image de Bouddha.</target>
      </trans-unit>       

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>About 30 villagers saw where Palden Dorje was meditating, and they left an offering of over a thousand rupees as was the custom at Buddha Jayanti.  On that night at 12:00,  some pranksters came to disturb Palden Dorje and steal the offering.  They quarreled over the money, and later accused each other in front of the villagers.  Having confessed, they asked Palden Dorje’s forgiveness.</source>
        <target>Environ trente villageois virent où Guru méditait et laissèrent une offrande de plus de mille roupies, comme il est de coutume le jour de Bouddha Jayanti. Cette nuit-là, à minuit, une bande de voyous vinrent déranger Guru et volèrent l'offrande. Ils se querellèrent ensuite concernant l'argent, et plus tard s'accusèrent les uns les autres devant les villageois. Ayant confessé, ils demandèrent le pardon de Guru.
		</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>So Palden Dorje left the first meditation place and went north on the 24th of May, 2005.  At that time he gave six pipal leaves to his second elder brother telling him to keep them in oil.  He said that as long as his family kept the leaves, all would be well.  His relatives cried when he left.</source>
        <target>Après quoi, ce dernier quitta le premier lieu de méditation et se dirigea vers le nord, le 24 mai 2005. A ce moment-là, il donna à son second frère aîné six feuilles de figuier en lui demandant de les conserver dans de l'huile. Il dit que tant que sa famille garderait les feuilles tout se passerait bien. Ses proches pleurèrent quand il les quitta.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Again the villagers were concerned about Palden Dorje’s whereabouts, and in the late afternoon, a cowherd had seen him in his new meditation site. The villagers sent some of his family to go and bring him home.  But Palden Dorje refused and  moved to another pipal tree in the east.</source>
        <target>De nouveau, les villageois s'inquiétèrent concernant le comportement de Guru. Tard dans l'après-midi, un fermier aperçut Guru à son nouveau lieu de méditation. Les villageois envoyèrent certains membres de sa famille afin de le ramener à sa maison. Mais Guru refusa et bougea vers un autre arbre figuier vers l'est.</target>
      </trans-unit>       

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje told his family that he must continue to meditate at all costs.  He drew a boundary around his meditation area, and the villagers and his relatives built a fence for him. More and more crowds gathered at the site, so Palden Dorje ordered that a hut be built and sealed with plastic on all sides wherein he remained for 15 days. After that Palden Dorje said, “I have received some energy so that I may now meditate under a tree outside”.</source>
        <target>Guru dit à sa famille qu'il lui fallait continuer sa méditation à tout prix. Il délimita un périmètre autour de l'arbre où il méditait et les villageois et ses proches y installèrent une clôture. De plus en plus de gens se rassemblèrent à cet endroit. Palden Dorje ordonna qu'une hutte soit construite et fermée avec du plastique de tous les côtés. Après quinze jours, Guru dit: “J'ai reçu une énergie particulière afin d'être capable de méditer sous un arbre.”.		
		</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>There was a terrible drought in the village. Palden Dorje told them to pray to a snake god and after 5 days, it started raining. In the 75th day of meditation, he opened the eyes and asked his elder brother to call him by the words: “Om Namó Gurú Búddha Gyáni”.</source>
        <target>Il y eut une terrible sécheresse au village. Palden Dorje les incita à prier un dieu serpent et après 5 jours, il commença à pleuvoir. À son 75ème jour de méditation, il ouvrit ses yeux et demanda à son frère aîné de l'appeler par les mots: “Om Namo Guru Buddha Gyáni”.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He returned to his meditation. Since that day he was addressed as</source>
        <target>Il retourna ensuite à sa méditation. Depuis ce jour, on s'adresse à lui en tant que</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>“Om Namo Guru Buddha Gyani”</source>
        <target>“Om Namo Guru Buddha Gyani”</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>(Hail to the Master of the Wisdom of Buddha.)</source>
        <target>(Salutation à celui qui obéit au Bouddha de la Sagesse)</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On August 18, 2005, Palden Dorje called together his friends who were lamas.  They asked him how it was that Palden Dorje was surviving without water. Palden Dorje replied that two snake gods protected him from either side.  That day Palden Dorje also changed his clothes and wore a white cloth called Ngag.</source>
        <target>Le 18 Août 2005, Guru appela quelques-uns de ses amis qui étaient lamas. Ces lamas lui demandèrent comment il se faisait qu'il puisse survivre sans boire ni manger; Guru répondit que deux dieux serpents le protégeaient de chaque côté. Ce jour-là, Palden Dorje changea également de vêtement, il s'habilla d'un vêtement blanc appelé 'Ngag'.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On November 6, 2005 snake bit Palden Dorje, and Palden Dorje’s body was poisoned. Palden Dorje sweated more than two liters while he continued to meditate, and thus he overcame the poison.  Palden Dorje’s followers believe that on that day he was enlightened, for the Bodhisattva has the ability to survive attached to a tree, soil and stone, to digest snake poison, to be unaffected by the wind and to understand the language of all creatures.</source>
        <target>Le 6 Novembre 2005, un serpent mordu Palden Dorje et son corps fut alors empoisonné. Guru transpira plus de deux litres tout en continuant à méditer, et ainsi surmonta l'épreuve. Les fidèles de Guru pensent qu'à partir de ce jour il atteignit l'illumination, puisqu'il est dit qu'un Bodhisattva a la capacité de survivre attaché à un arbre, au sol ou à un rocher, de digérer le poison d'un serpent, de ne pas être affecté par le vent et de comprendre le langage de toutes les créatures.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On November 8, 2005, Palden Dorje told the people that he did not have the energy of a Buddha, and he asked them not to publicize him as an incarnation of Buddha.</source>
        <target>Le 8 novembre 2005, Palden Dorje dit au gens qu'il n'avait pas l'énergie d'un Bouddha, et il leur demanda de ne pas faire de publicité de lui en tant que Bouddha.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On November 11, 2005 a bright light appeared shining from Palden Dorje’s head.  His followers cried with joy and became even more fervent.</source>
        <target>Le 11 novembre 2005, une lumière éclatante apparût au niveau de la tête de Guru. Ses disciples pleurèrent de joie et devinrent encore plus fervents.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>“Leave me in peace, and there will soon be peace in the country,” – Palden Dorje said. However crowds ever increased and people chanted and set up a market place, according to Radio HBC 94 FM who visited the site on December 10, 2005. The crowds were kept at a distance of about 50 meters. All witnesses claimed that Palden Dorje neither ate, drank or left to relieve himself.  He just sat and meditated under the pipal tree. Baffled onlookers were ever increasing.</source>
        <target>“Laissez-moi tranquille et il y aura bientôt la paix dans le pays.” dit Guru. Cependant la foule ne cessa d'augmenter, ils chantèrent et installèrent un marché. La foule était gardée à une distance de 50 mètres. Tous les témoins affirment que Guru ne mangea rien, ne bu rien, ni ne chercha à se soulager. Il restait simplement assis et méditait sous l'arbre figuier.</target>
      </trans-unit>      

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>There were stories of miracles: a</source>
        <target>Il y eut de plus en plus de spectateurs perplexes et des histoires de miracles apparurent: une</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>girl</source>
        <target>fille</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>and a young man had gained the power of speech although they could not speak.</source>
        <target>et un jeune garçon retrouvèrent l'usage de la parole, alors qu'ils étaient tous deux muets.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>After about ten months of meditation, Palden Dorje went missing on 11 March 2006. He gave no explanation, and some believed he had been abducted. His followers theorized that he went deeper into the woods to look for a quieter place to meditate.</source>
        <target>Après environ dix mois de méditation, Palden Dorje disparut le 11 Mars 2006. Il ne donna aucune explication et certaines personnes craignirent qu'il fut enlevé. Ses fidèles supposèrent plutôt qu'il soit allé plus profondément dans les bois afin de trouver un lieu plus calme où méditer.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Police abandoned a search for him after the possibility of foul play was eliminated. Suspecting money laundering, the authorities froze the bank account of the local committee managing the crowds, which had gathered more than Rs. 600,000 ($7950), but they found no evidence.</source>
        <target>La police abandonna les recherches après avoir éliminé la possibilité d'un enlèvement. Suspectant un blanchissement d'argent, les autorités bloquèrent le compte en banque du comité local qui s'occupe de gérer la foule, qui comptabilisa plus de 600,000 Rupees (7950$), mais ils ne trouvèrent aucune évidence.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 19 March, a group of Palden Dorje's followers met with him about 2 miles (3 kilometers) southwest of his meditation site. They say they spoke to him for thirty minutes, during which Palden Dorje said: "There is no peace here" and that he would return in six years, which would be in 2011 or 2012. He left a message for his parents telling them not to worry.</source>
        <target>Le 19 mars, un groupe de fidèles de Palden Dorje le rencontra à environ trois kilomètres au sud-ouest de son lieu de méditation. Ils ont reporté qu'ils parlèrent avec lui pendant une demi-heure, durant laquelle Palden Dorje leur dit: «  Il n'y a aucune tranquilité ici » et qu'il reviendrait d'ici six ans, c'est-à-dire en 2011 ou 2012. Il laissa également un message pour ses parents , leur disant de ne pas s'inquiéter.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 25 December 2006, villagers in Bara district spotted Palden Dorje meditating. He was carrying a sword for protection in the jungle, reminding reporters that "Even Gautama Buddha had to protect himself," and claimed to have eaten nothing but herbs in the interim.</source>
        <target>Le 25 décembre 2006, des villageois de la région de Bara aperçurent Palden Dorje en méditation. Il transportait avec lui une machette pour se protéger dans la jungle, rappelant aux journalistes que « Même le Bouddha devait se protéger. », et affirma n'avoir rien mangé à l'exception d'herbe durant cette période.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He reiterated his six year commitment to Buddhist devotion, and said he would allow people to come and observe him, as long as they remained at some distance and didn't bother him. When a reporter pointed out that pilgrims to his meditation site would be making donations in his name, he asked for the donations to not be abused or used for commercial purposes. A new wave of visitors came to see him and pray at his new meditation spot. On 8 March 2007 he left Bara district to again find a quieter place to meditate.</source>
        <target>Il réitéra son engagement à méditer en dévotion pendant six ans et dit qu'il accepterait que les gens viennent l'observer seulement s’ils restent à une certaine distance et qu'ils ne le dérangent pas. Quand un journaliste fit la remarque que les pèlerins laisseraient certainement des donations pour lui, il demanda qu'il n'y ait pas d'abus et que les donations ne soient pas utilisées à des fins commerciales.
Une nouvelle vague de visiteurs vint le voir et prièrent à son nouveau lieu de méditation. Le 8 mars 2007, il quitta la région de Bara afin de trouver à nouveau un endroit plus calme où méditer.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 26 March 2007, Inspector Rameshwor Yadav of the Area Police Post Nijgadh, found Palden Dorje inside a bunker-like ditch seven feet square. A police team under Yadav's command had gone to the place after word had spread of Palden Dorje meditating underground. “His face was clean and hair was combed well,” – Yadav said.</source>
        <target>Le 26 mars 2007, l'inspecteur Rameshwor Yadav du poste de police de Nijgadh trouva Palden Dorje à l'intérieur d'une sorte de trou/bunker de deux mètres carré. Une équipe de police, sous les ordres de Yadav, alla inspecter l'endroit après avoir entendu une rumeur disant que Palden Dorje méditerait sous terre. « Son visage était propre et ses cheveux bien peignés » reporta Yadav.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>According to him, the bunker had been cemented from all sides and fitted with a tiled roof. Indra Lama, a local deployed as Palden Dorje's caretaker since the beginning of his intensive meditation, said the bunker was prepared per Palden Dorje's request. “After granting audience a week ago, he expressed his desire to meditate inside the ground; so we built it,” – he said.</source>
        <target>Selon ses dires, le bunker a été cimenté de tous les côtés et scellé par une toiture en tuile. Lama Indra, un habitant local qui prend soin de Palden Dorje depuis le début, dit que le bunker fut construit après que Palden Dorje lui-même en fit la demande. « Après nous avoir accordé une audience il y a de cela une semaine, il exprima son désir de méditer sous terre. C'est pourquoi nous avons construit ce bunker. » dit-il.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 2 August 2007, Palden Dorje</source>
        <target>Le 2 août 2007, Palden Dorje</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>addressed a large crowd</source>
        <target>s'adressa à une large foule</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>in Halkoriya jungle in Bara district of southern Nepal. The Namo Buddha Tapoban Committee, which is devoted to looking after Palden Dorje, assembled the meeting.</source>
        <target>dans la jungle d'Halkoriya, dans la région de Bara au Népal. Le 'Namo Buddha Tapoban Committee', qui est un comité s'occupant de Palden Dorje, organisa la rencontre.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>A notice about the boy's first-ever preaching was broadcast by a local FM radio station, and the committee also invited people by telephone. Around three thousand people gathered to listen to Palden Dorje's address. A video was made of the event. According to Upendra Lamichhane, a blogger who wrote an article and took pictures of the meeting, Palden Dorje's message was, "The only way we can save this nation is through spirituality".</source>
        <target>Une annonce concernant le premier sermon du 'garçon' fut transmise via une radio FM locale. Le comité invita également des gens par téléphone. Environ trois mille personnes se rassemblèrent pour écouter le discours de Palden Dorje. L'évènement fut également filmé. Selon Upendra Lamichhane, un blogger qui écrivit un article et pris des photos de la rencontre, l'essence du message de Palden Dorje est: « La seule manière de sauver cette nation est au travers de la spiritualité. ».</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>This was his speech:</source>
        <target>Voici son discours:</target>
      </trans-unit>     

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje is a member of the</source>
        <target>Palden Dorje fait partie de la communauté des</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Tamang</source>
        <target>Tamang</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>community, of which a majority practices</source>
        <target>, qui pratiquent en grande majorité le</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Vajrayana Buddhism</source>
        <target>Bouddhisme Vajrayana</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje's story gained popularity because it resembled a legend from the Jataka Nidanakatha about</source>
        <target>L'histoire de Palden Dorje gagna en popularité parce qu'elle ressemble à une légende provenant du Jataka Nidanakatha concernant l'illumination du</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Gautama Buddha's</source>
        <target>Bouddha Gautama</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>enlightenment, so much so that some devotees claimed Palden Dorje was the reincarnation of a Buddha.</source>
        <target>. A un tel point que certains dévots clamèrent que Palden Dorje pourrait être la réincarnation d'un Bouddha.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>However, on 8 November 2005 Dorje arose and said: “Tell the people not to call me a Buddha. I don't have the Buddha's energy. I am at the level of a rimpoche.” A rimpoche is a teacher, which indicates he believes he has achieved a significant amount. He said that he will need six more years of meditation before he may become a Buddha.</source>
        <target>Cependant, le 8 novembre 2005, Palden Dorje se manifesta et dit: « Dites aux gens de ne pas m'appeler Bouddha. Je n'ai pas l'énergie d'un Bouddha. Je suis au niveau d'un rimpoche. » Un rimpoche est un enseignant, ce qui indique qu'il pense avoir déjà atteint un certain niveau. Il dit qu'il aurait besoin de six années supplémentaires de méditation avant qu'il puisse devenir un Bouddha.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>According to his followers, Palden Dorje may have reached the stage of a</source>
        <target>Selon ses fidèles, Palden Dorje pourrait avoir atteint le stage d'un</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Bodhisattva </source>
        <target>bodhisattva</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>a person on the path to attaining full enlightenment or buddhahood for the benefit of all sentient beings. According to the historical Buddha, Gautama Buddha, there were innumerable Buddhas before him and infinite Buddhas to come. Proponents also claim that Palden Dorje might also be</source>
        <target>, une personne en voie d'atteindre la parfaite illumination, ou 'état du Bouddha' pour le bienfait de tous les être sensibles. D'après le Bouddha historique, Gautama Bouddha, il y eut d'innombrable Bouddhas avant lui et encore plus à venir. D'autres affirment également que Palden Dorje pourrait être le bodhisattva</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Maitreya</source>
        <target>Maitreya</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Bodhisattva, the predicted successor to the historical Buddha.</source>
        <target>, le successeur prédit du Bouddha historique.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>His mother's name is Maya Devi Tamang, the same first name as Buddha's mother. It is reported that his mother fainted when she found out that her son intended to meditate for an indefinite period.</source>
        <target>Le nom de sa mère est Maya Devi Tamang, le même prénom que la mère du Bouddha. Il a été reporté que sa mère s'évanouit quand elle apprit que son fils comptait méditer pendant une période indéfinie.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Those who have called him the "reincarnation of Buddha" have been criticised. Gautama Buddha taught that after</source>
        <target>Ceux qui l'ont appelés la « réincarnation du Bouddha » ont été critiqués. Le Bouddha Gautama enseigna qu'il n'y a plus de renaissance après </target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>parinirvana</source>
        <target>parinirvana</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>there is no more rebirth, therefore it is impossible to be a "reincarnation of Buddha", but it is possible to be another Buddha, another who has attained, or will attain, enlightenment.</source>
        <target>. Il est donc impossible d'être une « réincarnation du Bouddha », mais il est possible d'être un autre Bouddha, qui a atteint ou s'apprête à atteindre l'illumination</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>An average human being who stops drinking will die of dehydration in three to four days. According to the Guinness Book of Records the longest time a human has survived without water is 18 days. Palden Dorje, on the other hand, does not appear to break his meditation to eat or drink.</source>
        <target>Normalement, un être humain qui arrête de boire meurt de déshydratation après trois ou quatre jours. D'après le livre des records Guinness, la plus longue période durant laquelle un être humain a survécu sans eau est de 18 jours. Palden Dorje ne semble pourtant pas interrompre sa méditation pour manger ou boire.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje was observed not to leave the tree at least during the daytime, but nobody was allowed to approach him too closely. Between 5:00 p.m. and 5:00 a.m. nobody was allowed to see him, and a screen was erected for that purpose. Many people speculated that he ate and drank water during that time.</source>
        <target>Même si personne n'était autorisé à l'approcher de trop près, il est certain qu'au moins durant la journée Palden Dorje ne quittait pas son lieu de méditation près de l'arbre. Cependant, entre 5 heures de l'après-midi et 5 heures du matin, personne n'était autorisé à le voir, une bâche était installée à ce propos. Beaucoup de gens spéculèrent qu'il profitait de ce moment pour se nourrir.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Some supporters believe that discussions of</source>
        <target>Certains fidèles pensent que les discussions autour de son</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inedia</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>inedia</source>
        <target>jeûne</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>are irrelevant, and that the ability to sit nearly motionless in the same position day after day, with no regard for extremes of weather including a cold winter and a monsoon season, is notable. For example, American writer George Saunders visited Palden Dorje and observed him through a single night, and was impressed by Palden Dorje's perfectly still stature, even during an evening climate that seemed unbearably cold to the much better clothed journalist.</source>
        <target>ne sont pas pertinentes, et que son habileté à rester assis immobile jour après jour dans la même posture, imperturbé par les climats extrêmes, est déjà en soi un exploit. Pour exemple, l'écrivain américain George Saunders, qui rendit visite à Palden Dorje et l'observa durant une nuit, fut impressionné par sa parfaite stature et ce, même durant une soirée qui sembla extrêmement froide pour ce journaliste qui était pourtant vêtu bien plus chaudement.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>In December 2005, a nine-member government committee led by Gunjaman Lama watched Palden Dorje carefully for 48 hours and observed him not to take any food or water during that time. A video recording was also made of this test. However, they were unable to approach closer than 3 meters or take readings of his vital signs. The Nepalese government planned a more careful scientific study, but the plan was never carried out.</source>
        <target>En décembre 2005, un comité gouvernemental constitué de neuf membres et mené par le Lama Gunjaman observa attentivement Palden Dorje pendant 48 heures et constata qu'il ne mangea ni ne bu durant cette période. Un enregistrement vidéo fut également réalisé pour ce test. Toutefois, il ne leur a pas été permis d'approcher à plus de trois mètres, ni de lire ses signes vitaux. Le gouvernement népalais projeta de faire une étude scientifique plus poussée, mais ce projet ne vit jamais le jour.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>In 2007, the Discovery Channel produced a documentary titled</source>
        <target>En 2007, la chaîne télévisée 'Discovery Channel' produisit un documentaire intitulé</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>The Boy With Divine Powers</source>
        <target>The Boy with Divine Powers (le Garçon aux Pouvoirs Divins)</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On their first, four-day attempt, the film crew was required to stay outside a guarded barbed-wire fence, and their camera's infrared capabilities did not pick up evidence of a body at the base of the tree where Palden Dorje sat during their non-stop recording. On a second attempt a few weeks later, however, the film crew was able to film Palden Dorje continuously for 96 hours, day and night, during which time he did not drink any fluids or eat any food. According to scientists on the documentary, an average person would be expected to die from kidney failure after four days without drinking any fluids. The boy showed no signs of classical physical deterioration caused by dehydration. A close inspection by the film crew of the area around the tree where Palden Dorje was sitting revealed no hidden food supply or water pipes.</source>
        <target>Durant leur premier essai de quatre jours, il fut demandé à l'équipe du film de ne pas aller au-delà d'une clôture en fils barbelés. Ils y installèrent une caméra à capacité infrarouge mais ne virent personne durant la totalité de leur enregistrement à l'endroit où Palden Dorje était supposé méditer. A leur deuxième essai, quelques semaines plus tard, l'équipe pu filmer Palden Dorje continuellement pendant 96 heures, jour et nuit, période durant laquelle il ne mangea rien ni ne bu. D'après les scientifiques dans le reportage, une personne ordinaire serait censée mourir d'une défaillance des reins après quatre jours sans boire. Le garçon, Palden Dorje, ne montra aucun des signes classiques d'une détérioration physique causée par déshydratation. Une inspection plus poussée de la zone par l'équipe du film ne révéla aucune trace de nourriture ou de conduit par lequel il pourrait boire.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 10 November 2008, Palden Dorje</source>
        <target>Le 8 novembre 2008, Palden Dorje</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>reappeared and spoke</source>
        <target>éapparut et parla</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>to a group of devotees in the remote jungle of Ratanpuri, 150 km (95 miles) southeast of Kathmandu, near Nijgadh. His hair was shoulder-length and his body was wrapped in a white cloth.</source>
        <target>à un groupe de dévots dans la jungle isolée de Ratanpuri (150 km, 95 miles, sud-est de Kathmandu, près de Nijgadh). Ses cheveux lui arrivaient aux épaules et son corps était enveloppé d'un vêtement blanc.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>His devotees believe he attained enlightenment at Bodh Gaya in Bihar, which borders Nepal – the place where Siddartha Gautama attained enlightenment.</source>
        <target>Ses fidèles pensent qu'il atteignit l'illumination à Bodh Gaya (Bihar), lieu qui se trouve à la frontière du Népal et où Siddhartha Gautama lui-même réalisa l'illumination.</target>
      </trans-unit>

    </body>
  </file>
</xliff>