<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<xliff version="1.0">
  <file original="global" source-language="en" datatype="plaintext">
    <body>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Dharma Sangha - Biography - eTapasvi.com</source>
        <target>Dharma Sangha - Biografia- eTapasvi.com</target>
      </trans-unit>

<!-- showSuccess -->
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Family and Childhood</source>
        <target>Rodzina i dzieciństwo</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>School and Religious Education</source>
        <target>Szkoła i edukacja religijna</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje's Illness</source>
        <target>Choroba Paldena Dorje</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje Disappears</source>
        <target>Palden Dorje znika</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Meditation Begins</source>
        <target>Początek medytacji</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Snakebite and Miracles</source>
        <target>Ukąszenie węża i cuda</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Wandering to Bara district</source>
        <target>Wędrowanie do dystryktu Bara</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Meditating in pit</source>
        <target>Medytowanie w bunkrze</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Preaching in Halkoriya jungle</source>
        <target>Przemówienie w dżungli Halkoriya</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Buddhist background</source>
        <target>Buddyjskie korzenie</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Feats of inedia</source>
        <target>Praktykowanie inedii (niejedzenia)</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Reappearance in Ratanpuri jungle</source>
        <target>Wystąpienie w dżungli Ratanpuri</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>New Appearance in 2009</source>
        <target>Nowe wystąpienie w 2009 roku</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Dharma Sangha (earlier Palden Dorje, born Ram Bahadur Bomjan) was born on April 9, 1990 in Ratanpuri village, Bara district, Nepal.</source>
        <target>Dharma Sangha (wcześniej Palden Dorje, urodzony jako Ram Bahadur Bomjan) urodził się 9 kwietnia 1990 roku w wiosce Ratanpuri, w dystrykcie Bara  w Nepalu.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Ram’s parents are farmers. His mother, Maya Devi was married at 12.  She had 5 sons and 4 daughters.  Ram was her third son.  When she was in her pregnancy, she found she was unable to eat meat without becoming ill.  The son, whom she named Ram, would not eat meat.  He would leave the house for long intervals from an early age.</source>
        <target>Rodzice Rama są rolnikami. Jego matka, Maja Devi wyszła za mąż mając 12 lat. Miała 5 synów i 4 córki. Ram był jej trzecim synem. Będąc z nim w ciąży, odkryła że nie była w stanie zjeść mięsa bez zachorowania. Syn ten, którego nazwała Ram, nie jadał mięsa.  Od wczesnych lat opuszczał dom na dłuższe okresy czasu.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Ram was always pleased to see a lama or a holy person and fastidiously imitated them.  He often seemed to be lost in thought and spoke little.  Whenever someone spoke to him, he would reply with a smile and would treat people of all ages equally.</source>
        <target>Ram zawsze cieszył się z zobaczenia lamy, czy osoby duchownej i skrupulatnie ich naśladował. Często wydawał się być pogrążonym w myślach i niewiele mówił. Gdy ktoś zwracał się do niego, odpowiadał z uśmiechem i traktował ludzi równo, bez względu na ich wiek.</target>
      </trans-unit>
  
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>According to his family and neighbors, Ram Bomjan often acted differently from his childhood friends, frequently observing other people in worship and praying himself. He has been described as being born with a peaceful nature, and would never get into a fight or kill an animal. Beginning at the age of five he only took leftovers for food, and went hungry if there was nothing.</source>
        <target>Według rodziny i sąsiadów, Ram Bomjon zachowywał się często inaczej niż jego przyjaciele z dzieciństwa, wielokrotnie obserwował innych ludzi w modlitwie i sam się modlił. Określają go jako kogoś urodzonego o spokojnej naturze, nigdy nie wdającego się w bójki, czy zabijającego zwierzę. Począwszy od wieku 5 lat żywił się jedynie resztkami, a gdy nic nie zostawało po jedzeniu, chodził głodny.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He took his studies seriously and rarely played with other children, choosing instead to remain alone. He spent his time reading scriptures, meditating and worshipping the pipal tree which seemed to bring him joy. Seeing this behavior, Ram’s father sent him to study the scriptures of Lama Chhyoi with Samden Lama in their village.  After that Ram decided to embrace a religious life.</source>
        <target>Poważnie traktował naukę i rzadko bawił się z innymi dziećmi, wybierając w zamian samotność. Spędzał czas czytając pisma święte, medytując i czcząc swięte drzewo figowe, co zdawało się sprawiać mu radość. Widząc takie zachowanie, ojciec Rama wysłał go na studiowanie pism świętych Lamy Chhyoi z Samden Lama w ichniejszej wiosce. Po tym Ram zdecydował się wybrać życie religijne.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He was accepted into the monkhood by Som Bahadur Lama of Sudha, Ward 8 of Chitwan Village Development Committee.</source>
        <target>Został przyjęty do mnichów przez Som Bahadur Lama z Sudha, 8-go oddziału Komitetu Rozwoju Wioski Chitwan.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Som Bahadur Lama said the following of his ward: “He was obedient. He never said ‘no’ to my word. He was friendly and sociable and he received education in that manner. He used to say frequently that his attention was much more drawn towards meditation than towards reading books.”</source>
        <target>Som Bahadur Lama tak mówi o swym podopiecznym: "Był posłuszny. Nigdy nie sprzeciwiał się memu słowu. Był przyjazny i towarzyski i w ten sposób otrzymał edukację. Często powtarzał, że jego uwagę przyciągała znacznie bardziej medytacja niż czytanie książek.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He was granted the initiation of</source>
        <target>Otrzymał inicjację</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Panchasheel</source>
        <target>Panchasheel</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Panchasheel is a Sanskrit word for a Buddhist initiation consisting of five vows, which are as follows:</source>
        <target>Panchasheel jest to słowo z sanskrytu określające buddyjską inicjację składającą się z 5 następujących przysięg:</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must not kill animals (it is preferable to be vegetarian)</source>
        <target>Nie wolno zabijać zwierząt (preferowane jest bycie wegetarianinem)</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must not steal</source>
        <target>Nie wolno kraść</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must not lie</source>
        <target>Nie wolno kłamać</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must refrain from sexual misconduct</source>
        <target>Nie wolno myśleć negatywnie o innych</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must not take intoxicating substances</source>
        <target>Nie wolno zażywać substancji odurzających</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Ram was initiated along with a group of nine other students. Ram refused to have his hair cut before the initiation, which was the common custom. It was after this initiation that Ram received the name,</source>
        <target>Ram przeszedł inicjację wraz z grupą dziewięciu innych uczniów. Ram odmówił obcięcia włosów przed inicjacją, co było powszechnym zwyczajem. To właśnie po tej inicjacji Ram został nazwany</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje</source>
        <target>Palden Dorje</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>It was the custom for the initiates to meditate for up to a month in a cave. Som Bahadur Lama was surprised at the ease with which Palden Dorje seemed to adapt to the situation requiring little sustenance. It was then that he realized that the boy had a natural talent for deep and prolonged meditation.</source>
        <target>Dla inicjantów w zwyczaju było medytować w podziemiu przez okres trwający nawet do miesiąca. Lama Som Bahadur zaskoczony był łatwością z jaką Palden Dorje zdawał się przystosować do tej sytuacji wymagającej niewiele wyżywienia. To właśnie wtedy uświadomił sobie że chłopiec miał naturalną zdolność do głębokiej i przedłużającej się medytacji.</target>
	  </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>After completing his Buddhist education for two years, all nine initiates went to Lumbini, the birthplace of Lord Buddha, for sightseeing. Palden Dorje seemed utterly taken by this place and it seemed to deepen his religious resolve. The other eight initiates returned but he refused to return. Instead, he went to Dehradun to further his religious education with the Gurus of Dehradun. Later he returned to Nepal to the beautiful lakeside city of Pokhara.</source>
        <target>Po zakończeniu dwuletniej edukacji buddyjskiej, wszyscy inicjańci, a bylo ich dziewięciu, pojechali zwiedzać Lumbini, miejsce urodzenia Lorda Buddy. Palden Dorje zdawał się być pod wielkim wrażeniem tego miejsca i zapewne pogłębiło to jego religijne postanowienie. Pozostali inicjanci wrócili, lecz on odmówił powrotu. W zamian, udał się do Dehradun by pogłębiać wiedzę religijną pod okiem Guru(l.mn)z Dehradun i później powrócił do pięknego miasta Pokhara położonego nad brzegiem jeziora.</target>
	  </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Here it was that Palden Dorje became ill, and was unable to move his lower body.  Distressed, his teachers sent him home to recover.  During this time, Palden Dorje implored his family not to sacrifice any animals or take any alcohol otherwise further complications would arise.  He got better, but was still limping when he disappeared from his home the night of  May 16, 2005.</source>
        <target>Wracając do domu z Dehradun, zachorował, i nie był w stanie poruszać dolną częścią ciała. Tak osłabionego, nauczyciele odesłali do domu, aby tam powrócił do zdrowia. Wtedy to Palden Dorje upraszał rodzinę by zaniechali poświęcania ofierze jakichkolwiek zwierząt, czy spożywania alkoholu, w przeciwnym razie mogłyby nastąpić dalsze komplikacje. Poczuł się lepiej, ale wciąż kulał, gdy zniknął z domu w nocy 16 maja 2005 roku.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>When his mother became aware of the situation, she alerted the village, and everyone joined in the search for him.  A local boy claimed to have seen him while he was shaking a mango tree.  Palden Dorje had come up and picked up a mango, and stepped fully clothed into the river. “I thought you had disappeared,” – the boy remarked to Palden Dorje.</source>
        <target>Gdy jego matka zdała sobie sprawę z tej sytuacji, powiadomiła o tym całą wioskę, i każdy przyłączył się do poszukiwań. Miejscowy chłopiec twierdził, że widział go, gdy potrząsał drzewo mangowe. Palden Dorje podszedł i podniósł jedno mango, a następnie wszedł w pełnym odzieniu do rzeki. "Myślałem, że zaginąłeś" zwrócił się chłopiec do Paldena Dorje.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>“Have I?” – Palden Dorje  replied. – “You’d better go home, and be careful not to touch me.” The boy ran home to tell his story, but nobody believed him at first.  Palden Dorje’s relatives went to the ravine.  Palden Dorje smiled at them when they found him as was his habit.  They told him to come home.  “I’ll go home at four o’clock,” – Palden Dorje said.  His family decided it would be wise to keep an eye on him, and so some of his siblings stayed with him.</source>
        <target>"Zaginąłem?" odparł Palden Dorje. "Lepiej wracaj do domu i uważaj żebyś mnie nie dotknął." Chłopak pobiegł do domu opowiedzieć tę historię, ale nikt mu najpierw nie wierzył. Krewni Paldena Dorje udali się do tego jaru. Palden Dorje uśmiechnął się do nich, gdy go odnaleźli, jak to miał w zwyczaju robić. Powiedzieli mu, by wracał do domu. "Wrócę do domu o godzinie czwartej." Powiedział Palden Dorje. Jego rodzina zdecydowała, że byłoby lepiej mieć go na oku, więc kilkoro rodzeństwa zostało przy nim.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>At four o’clock, he picked up a couple of mangoes and began to eat one.  He told his little brother to bring him water, rice, his lama robes, a rosary and a picture of Buddha.  His little brother obeyed.  Palden Dorje’s sister came to tell Palden Dorje to come home at once.  Seeing how emaciated he looked from his previous  illness, she cried and begged him to come home.  Palden Dorje told her to stop crying, and she went home.</source>
        <target>O czwartej godzinie, wybrał kilka owoców mango i zaczął jeść jeden z nich. Poprosił młodszego brata by przyniósł mu wodę, ryż, jego ubiory lamy, różaniec i obrazek z Buddą. Jego młodszy brat spełnił prośbę. Siostra Paldena Dorje przyszła mu powiedzieć, by natychmiast wracał do domu. Widząc jak szczupło wyglądał po poprzedzającej chorobie, płakała i błagała go, by wrócił do domu. Palden Dorje powiedział jej, by przestała płakać i poszła do domu.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Then Palden Dorje, sitting in a meditative posture seemed to go into a trance.  He began to ask himself questions and answer them out loud. The other villagers came and told Palden Dorje to stop being silly and come home.</source>
        <target>Potem, siedząc w pozycji medytacyjnej, Palden Dorje zdawał się pogrążyć w transie. Zaczął zadawać sobie pytania i odpowiadać na głos. Inni mieszkańcy wioski przyszli mu powiedzieć by przestał zachowywać się niemądrze i wracał do domu.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>They feared he must be ill or crazy.  When Palden Dorje’s older brother touched him, Palden Dorje’s body became exceedingly hot and turned red. “Please leave me alone, or one of us may die,” – Palden Dorje said. – “If anyone disturbs me or my things at midnight, I will have to meditate for 20 years, but if all goes well, I will meditate for 6 years.”</source>
        <target>Bali się, że pewnie jest chory, albo stracił rozum. Gdy starszy brat Paldena Dorje dotknął go, ciało Paldena Dorje stało się nadzwyczaj gorące i poczerwieniało. "Proszę, zostawcie mnie samego, w przeciwnym razie ktoś z nas może umrzeć." powiedział Palden Dorje. Jeśli ktokolwiek czepi się mnie lub moich rzeczy o północy, będę zmuszony medytować 20 lat, ale jeśli wszystko pójdzie dobrze, będę medytować przez lat 6."</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Then Palden Dorje, followed by his brother, and at a distance by the villagers set out to find a good meditation  place in the forest. His parents insisted he take some food and water with him.  Finally, he reached his destination  at 11:00 AM on May 18, 2005. This was the day the villagers of Ratanpuri celebrated</source>
        <target>Potem, Palden Dorje, za którym podążał jego brat, a w większej odległości mieszkańcy wsi, wyruszył w poszukiwaniu odpowiedniego miejsca medytacyjnego w lesie. Jego rodzice nalegali, by wziął ze sobą trochę żywności i wody. W końcu, dotarł do wyznaczonego miejsca o godzinie 11:00 przed południem, 18 maja 2005 roku. Był to dzień świątecznych obchodów w wiosce Ratanpuri.</target>
      </trans-unit>      

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vesak</source>
        <target>http://pl.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vesak</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Buddha Jayanti (Vesak)</source>
        <target>Budda Jayanti (Vesak)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He settled himself under a pipal tree, having offered 10 kinds of fruit to the picture of Buddha.</source>
        <target>Rozłożył się pod drzewem figowym, ofiarując uprzednio 10 rodzajów owoców wizerunkowi Buddy.</target>
      </trans-unit>      

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>About 30 villagers saw where Palden Dorje was meditating, and they left an offering of over a thousand rupees as was the custom at Buddha Jayanti.  On that night at 12:00,  some pranksters came to disturb Palden Dorje and steal the offering.  They quarreled over the money, and later accused each other in front of the villagers.  Having confessed, they asked Palden Dorje’s forgiveness.</source>
        <target>Około 30 mieszkańców widziało, gdzie Palden Dorje medytował i zostawili oni ofiarę w postaci ponad tysiąca rupii, co było zwyczajem w święto Budda Jayanti. Tej nocy o 12:00, kilku dowcipnisiów przyszło, by dokuczyć Paldenowi Dorje i ukraść ofiarę. Pokłócili się oni o pieniądze, a później oskarżali siebie nawzajem przed mieszkańcami wioski. Przyznawszy się do winy, poprosili Paldena Dorje o przebaczenie.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>So Palden Dorje left the first meditation place and went north on the 24th of May, 2005.  At that time he gave six pipal leaves to his second elder brother telling him to keep them in oil.  He said that as long as his family kept the leaves, all would be well.  His relatives cried when he left.</source>
        <target>Wobec tego, Palden Dorje opuścił to pierwsze miejsce medytacyjne i 24-go maja 2005 roku wyruszył na północ. Wtedy to dał swemu drugiemu starszemu bratu sześć liści figowych, prosząc go, by przechowywał je w oliwie. Powiedział, że jak długo rodzina jego będzie je mieć pod ochroną, wszystko dobrze się potoczy.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Again the villagers were concerned about Palden Dorje’s whereabouts, and in the late afternoon, a cowherd had seen him in his new meditation site. The villagers sent some of his family to go and bring him home.  But Palden Dorje refused and  moved to another pipal tree in the east.</source>
        <target>Znów mieszkańcy wsi niepokoili się o to, gdzie przebywa Palden Dorje, a późnym popołudniem pastuch widział go w nowym miejscu medytacji. Miejscowi posłali kilku członków jego rodziny, by poszli po niego i zaprowadzili do domu. Lecz Palden Dorje odmówił i przeszedł na wschód pod inne drzewo figowe.</target>
      </trans-unit>      

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje told his family that he must continue to meditate at all costs.  He drew a boundary around his meditation area, and the villagers and his relatives built a fence for him. More and more crowds gathered at the site, so Palden Dorje ordered that a hut be built and sealed with plastic on all sides wherein he remained for 15 days. After that Palden Dorje said, “I have received some energy so that I may now meditate under a tree outside”.</source>
        <target>Palden Dorje powiedział rodzinie, że musi za wszelką cenę kontynuować medytację. Naznaczył granice wokół jego miejsca medytacji, a mieszkańcy wsi i jego krewni zbudowali dla niego ogrodzenie. Coraz większe tłumy ściągały do tego miejsca, więc Palden Dorje zlecił wybudowanie budy ograniczonej ze wszystkich stron plastikiem, gdzie pozostał przez 15 dni. Po tym, Palden Dorje rzekł: "Otrzymałem już na tyle energii, że mogę teraz medytować na zewnątrz pod drzewem".</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>There was a terrible drought in the village. Palden Dorje told them to pray to a snake god and after 5 days, it started raining. In the 75th day of meditation, he opened the eyes and asked his elder brother to call him by the words: “Om Namó Gurú Búddha Gyáni”.</source>
        <target>W wiosce panowała ogromna susza. Palden Dorje przekazał, by modlić się do boga-węża i po 5 dniach zaczęło padać. W 75-tym dniu medytacji, otworzył oczy i poprosił starszego brata, by zwracać się do niego słowami: “Om Namo Guru Budda Gyani”.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He returned to his meditation. Since that day he was addressed as</source>
        <target>Powrócił do swej medytacji. Od tego dnia zwracano się do niego jako</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>“Om Namo Guru Buddha Gyani”</source>
        <target>“Om Namo Guru Budda Gyani”</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>(Hail to the Master of the Wisdom of Buddha.)</source>
        <target>(Pozdrowienie tego, który zna Buddę)</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On August 18, 2005, Palden Dorje called together his friends who were lamas.  They asked him how it was that Palden Dorje was surviving without water. Palden Dorje replied that two snake gods protected him from either side.  That day Palden Dorje also changed his clothes and wore a white cloth called Ngag.</source>
        <target>18-go sierpnia 2005 roku Palden Dorje zwołał swoich przyjaciół, którzy byli lamami. Oni to zapytali go jak Palden Dorje potrafi przeżyć bez wody. Palden Dorje odrzekł, że dwaj bogowie-węże chronią go z każdej strony. Tego dnia Palden Dorje zmienił również swe ubranie i włożył białe płótno zwane Ngag.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On November 6, 2005 snake bit Palden Dorje, and Palden Dorje’s body was poisoned. Palden Dorje sweated more than two liters while he continued to meditate, and thus he overcame the poison.  Palden Dorje’s followers believe that on that day he was enlightened, for the Bodhisattva has the ability to survive attached to a tree, soil and stone, to digest snake poison, to be unaffected by the wind and to understand the language of all creatures.</source>
        <target>6-go listopada 2005 roku Paldena Dorje ukąsił wąż i ciało Paldena Dorje zostało zatrute. Palden Dorje wypocił ponad 2 litry kontynułując medytację, i tak przezwyciężył truciznę. Zwolennicy Paldena Dorje uważają, iż tego dnia został oświecony, ponieważ Bodhisattwa posiada umiejętność przeżycia bedąc przytwierdzonym do drzewa, ziemi, czy skały, strawienia trucizny jadu węża, bycia nietkniętym przez wiatr, i rozumienia języka wszystkich stworzeń.</target>
      </trans-unit>            

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On November 8, 2005, Palden Dorje told the people that he did not have the energy of a Buddha, and he asked them not to publicize him as an incarnation of Buddha.</source>
        <target>8 października 2005 roku Palden Dorje przekazał ludziom, że nie ma on energii Buddy, i poprosił by nie rozgłaszać o nim jako o inkarnacji Buddy.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On November 11, 2005 a bright light appeared shining from Palden Dorje’s head.  His followers cried with joy and became even more fervent.</source>
        <target>11 listopada 2005 roku jasne światło zawidniało promieniując z głowy Paldena Dorje. Jego zwolennicy płakali z radości i stali się jeszcze bardziej gorliwi.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>“Leave me in peace, and there will soon be peace in the country,” – Palden Dorje said. However crowds ever increased and people chanted and set up a market place, according to Radio HBC 94 FM who visited the site on December 10, 2005. The crowds were kept at a distance of about 50 meters. All witnesses claimed that Palden Dorje neither ate, drank or left to relieve himself.  He just sat and meditated under the pipal tree. Baffled onlookers were ever increasing.</source>
        <target>"Zostawcie mnie w pokoju, a wkrótce zapanuje pokój w państwie," rzekł Palden Dorje. Jednakże tłumy stale rosły, a ludzie śpiewali pieśni i rozstawiali kramy, według Radia HBC 94 FM, które odwiedziło to miejsce 10-go grudnia 2005 roku. Tłumy oddalono na odleglość 50 metrow. Wszyscy świadkowie twierdzili, że Palden Dorje ani nie jadł, ani nie pił, ani też nie odchodził za potrzebą. Po prostu siedział i medytował pod drzewem figowym.  Przybywało coraz więcej zdumionych widzów.</target>
      </trans-unit>      

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>There were stories of miracles: a</source>
        <target>Opowiadano o cudach:</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>girl</source>
        <target>dziewczynka</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>and a young man had gained the power of speech although they could not speak.</source>
        <target>i młody mężczyzna zyskali moc mówienia, mimo że wcześniej nie mogli mówić.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>After about ten months of meditation, Palden Dorje went missing on 11 March 2006. He gave no explanation, and some believed he had been abducted. His followers theorized that he went deeper into the woods to look for a quieter place to meditate.</source>
        <target>Po około dziesięciu miesiącach medytacji, Palden Dorje zaginął 11 marca 2006. Nie podał żadnego wytłumaczenia, i niektórzy myśleli, że został uprowadzony. Jego stronnicy snuli teorie, że przeszedł głębiej do lasu w poszukiwaniu spokojniejszego miejsca do medytacji.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Police abandoned a search for him after the possibility of foul play was eliminated. Suspecting money laundering, the authorities froze the bank account of the local committee managing the crowds, which had gathered more than Rs. 600,000 ($7950), but they found no evidence.</source>
        <target>Policja zaniechała jego poszukiwań po tym, jak wykluczono możliwość nieuczciwej gry. Podejrzewając pranie pieniędzy, władze zamroziły konto bankowe miejscowego stowarzyszenia kierującego tłumem odwiedzających, który zebrał więcej niż 600 000 rupii ($7950), ale nie znaleźli żadnego dowodu.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 19 March, a group of Palden Dorje's followers met with him about 2 miles (3 kilometers) southwest of his meditation site. They say they spoke to him for thirty minutes, during which Palden Dorje said: "There is no peace here" and that he would return in six years, which would be in 2011 or 2012. He left a message for his parents telling them not to worry.</source>
        <target>19 marca, grupa zwolenników Paldena Dorje spotkała się z nim około 2 mile (3 kilometry) na południe od jego miejsca medytacji. Mówią, że rozmawiali z nim trzydzieści minut, podczas których Palden Dorje powiedział "Nie ma tu spokoju" i że wróci za 6 lat, co przypada na 2011 lub 2012 rok. Zostawił wiadomość dla swych rodziców, aby nie niepokoili się o niego.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 25 December 2006, villagers in Bara district spotted Palden Dorje meditating. He was carrying a sword for protection in the jungle, reminding reporters that "Even Gautama Buddha had to protect himself," and claimed to have eaten nothing but herbs in the interim.</source>
        <target>25 grudnia 2006 roku, mieszkańcy wioski w dystrykcie Bara zauważyli medytującego Paldena Dorje. Mając przy sobie sztylet służący do ochrony w dżungli, przypomniał dziennikarzom, że "Nawet Guatama Budda musiał się chronić przed niebezpieczeństwem" i twierdził, że nie jadł nic prócz traw w międzyczasie.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He reiterated his six year commitment to Buddhist devotion, and said he would allow people to come and observe him, as long as they remained at some distance and didn't bother him. When a reporter pointed out that pilgrims to his meditation site would be making donations in his name, he asked for the donations to not be abused or used for commercial purposes. A new wave of visitors came to see him and pray at his new meditation spot. On 8 March 2007 he left Bara district to again find a quieter place to meditate.</source>
        <target>Potwierdził swoje sześcioletnie zobowiązanie do buddyjskiej praktyki, i powiedział, że zezwoli ludziom przybywać i przyglądać się mu, jeśli tylko zachowają odpowiednią odległość i nie będą mu przeszkadzać. Gdy reporter zaznaczył, że pielgrzymi będą ofiarować datki w jego intencji, poprosił by nie nadużywać datków, czy też wydawać na cele komercjalne. Nowa fala odwiedzających przybyła, aby go zobaczyć i modlić się w jego nowym punkcie medytacyjnym. 8-go marca opuścił dystrykt Bara, by znów znaleźć spokojniejsze miejsce do medytacji.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 26 March 2007, Inspector Rameshwor Yadav of the Area Police Post Nijgadh, found Palden Dorje inside a bunker-like ditch seven feet square. A police team under Yadav's command had gone to the place after word had spread of Palden Dorje meditating underground. “His face was clean and hair was combed well,” – Yadav said.</source>
        <target>26 marca 2007 roku, inspektor Rameshwor Yadav z policyjnego posterunku Nijgadh, zastał Paldena Dorje wewnątrz rowu na kształt bunkru o powierzchni 7 stóp. Brygada policyjna udała się tam pod komendą Yadava po tym jak rozniosły się wieści o medytującym pod ziemią Paldenie Dorje. "Jego twarz była czysta, a włosy dobrze uczesane" przekazał Yadav.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>According to him, the bunker had been cemented from all sides and fitted with a tiled roof. Indra Lama, a local deployed as Palden Dorje's caretaker since the beginning of his intensive meditation, said the bunker was prepared per Palden Dorje's request. “After granting audience a week ago, he expressed his desire to meditate inside the ground; so we built it,” – he said.</source>
        <target>Według niego, bunkier był ocementowany ze wszystkich stron i przykryty dachówkami. Lama Indra, miejscowy wyznaczony na opiekuna Paldena Dorje od samego początku jego intensywnej medytacji, powiedział że bunkier został przygotowany na prośbę Paldena Dorje. "Po udzieleniu audiencji tydzień temu, wyraził pragnienie medytowania wewnątrz ziemi; więc wybudowaliśmy to." stwierdził.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 2 August 2007, Palden Dorje</source>
        <target>2-go sierpnia 2007 roku, Palden Dorje</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>addressed a large crowd</source>
        <target>zwrócił się do wielkiego zgromadzenia</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>in Halkoriya jungle in Bara district of southern Nepal. The Namo Buddha Tapoban Committee, which is devoted to looking after Palden Dorje, assembled the meeting.</source>
        <target>w dżungli Halkoriya w dystrykcie Bara w południowym Nepalu. Komitet Namo Budda Tapoban, który jest poświęcony opiece nad Paldenem Dorje, zwołał to zgromadzenie.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>A notice about the boy's first-ever preaching was broadcast by a local FM radio station, and the committee also invited people by telephone. Around three thousand people gathered to listen to Palden Dorje's address. A video was made of the event. According to Upendra Lamichhane, a blogger who wrote an article and took pictures of the meeting, Palden Dorje's message was, "The only way we can save this nation is through spirituality".</source>
        <target>Wiadomość o pierwszym jak dotąd przemówieniu chłopca została nadana przez lokalną radiostację FM, a komitet zapraszał również osoby za pośrednictwem telefonu. Około trzy tysiące ludzi zebrało się, by wysłuchać przekazu Paldena Dorje. Powstało nagranie wideo z tego wydarzenia. Upendra Lamichhane, bloger który napisał artykuł i zrobił zdjęcia ze spotkania, twierdzi, że przekaz Paldena Dorje to: "Jedynym sposobem na ocalenie tej nacji jest duchowość".</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>This was his speech:</source>
        <target>Oto jego wypowiedź:</target>
      </trans-unit>     

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje is a member of the</source>
        <target>Palden Dorje jest członkiem</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Tamang</source>
        <target>społeczności Tamang,</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>community, of which a majority practices</source>
        <target>w której większość praktykuje</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Vajrayana Buddhism</source>
        <target>Buddyzm Wadżrajana</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje's story gained popularity because it resembled a legend from the Jataka Nidanakatha about</source>
        <target>Historia Paldena Dorje zyskała popularność, ponieważ przypominała legendę ze wstępu Nidanakatha opowieści Dżataka o oświeceniu</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Gautama Buddha's</source>
        <target>Buddy Gautama</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>enlightenment, so much so that some devotees claimed Palden Dorje was the reincarnation of a Buddha.</source>
        <target>do tego stopnia, że niektórzy wielbiciele twierdzili, iż Palden Dorje jest reinkarnacją Buddy.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>However, on 8 November 2005 Dorje arose and said: “Tell the people not to call me a Buddha. I don't have the Buddha's energy. I am at the level of a rimpoche.” A rimpoche is a teacher, which indicates he believes he has achieved a significant amount. He said that he will need six more years of meditation before he may become a Buddha.</source>
        <target>Jednakże, 8-go listopada Dorje powstał i powiedział: "Przekaż ludziom, by nie nazywali mnie Buddą. Nie mam energii Buddy. Jestem na poziomie rinpocze". Rinpocze to nauczyciel, co oznacza, że wierzy on, iż osiągnął znacząco dużo. Powiedział, że bądzie potrzebował jeszcze sześciu lat medytacji, by stać się Buddą.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>According to his followers, Palden Dorje may have reached the stage of a</source>
        <target>Według jego stronników, Palden Dorje mógł osiągnąć poziom</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Bodhisattva </source>
        <target>Bodhisattwy</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>a person on the path to attaining full enlightenment or buddhahood for the benefit of all sentient beings. According to the historical Buddha, Gautama Buddha, there were innumerable Buddhas before him and infinite Buddhas to come. Proponents also claim that Palden Dorje might also be</source>
        <target>osoby na ścieżce do osiągnięcia pełnego oświecenia, czy poziomu Buddy na korzyść wszystkich żyjących (odczuwających) istot. Podług historycznego Buddy, Buddy Gautama, już przed nim było niezliczenie wielu buddów, a i po nim niezliczenie wielu Buddów przybędzie. Zwolennicy twierdzą również, że Palden Dorje mógłby także być</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Maitreya</source>
        <target>Maitreja</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Bodhisattva, the predicted successor to the historical Buddha.</source>
        <target>Bodhissatwą, przepowiedzianym następcą po historycznym Buddzie.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>His mother's name is Maya Devi Tamang, the same first name as Buddha's mother. It is reported that his mother fainted when she found out that her son intended to meditate for an indefinite period.</source>
        <target>Jego matka nosi imię Maya Devi Tamang, takie samo imię jak matka Buddy. Twierdzi się, że jego matka zemdlała, gdy dowiedziała się, że jej syn zamierza medytować przez nieokreślony okres czasu.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Those who have called him the "reincarnation of Buddha" have been criticised. Gautama Buddha taught that after</source>
        <target>Ci, którzy nazwali go "reinkarnacją Buddy" zostali skrytykowani. Budda Gautama nauczał, że po</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>parinirvana</source>
        <target>parinirwanie</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>there is no more rebirth, therefore it is impossible to be a "reincarnation of Buddha", but it is possible to be another Buddha, another who has attained, or will attain, enlightenment.</source>
        <target>nie ma więcej ponownych narodzin, dlatego też niemożliwym jest bycie "reinkarnacją Buddy", ale możliwe jest bycie kolejnym buddą, kolejnym, który osiągnął, bądź osiągnie, oświecenie.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>An average human being who stops drinking will die of dehydration in three to four days. According to the Guinness Book of Records the longest time a human has survived without water is 18 days. Palden Dorje, on the other hand, does not appear to break his meditation to eat or drink.</source>
        <target>Przeciętna ludzka istota, która przestanie przyjmować płyny, umrze z powodu odwodnienia po trzech, czterech dniach. Według Księgi Rekordów Guinnessa, najdłuższy okres jaki człowiek przeżył bez wody  to 18 dni. Palden Dorje, natomiast, nie wydaje się przerywać swej medytacji, by jeść, czy pić.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje was observed not to leave the tree at least during the daytime, but nobody was allowed to approach him too closely. Between 5:00 p.m. and 5:00 a.m. nobody was allowed to see him, and a screen was erected for that purpose. Many people speculated that he ate and drank water during that time.</source>
        <target>Zaobserwowano, że Palden Dorje nie opuszczał drzewa przynajmniej w dzień, ale nikomu nie pozwolono podejść do niego zbyt blisko. Między 5:00 po południu a 5:00 rano nikomu nie pozwalano go zobaczyć i zasłaniający ekran został wzniesiony w tym celu. Wielu spekulowało, że jadł wtedy i pił wodę.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Some supporters believe that discussions of</source>
        <target>Niektórzy stronnicy uważają, że dyskusje na temat</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inedia</source>
        <target>http://pl.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inedia</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>inedia</source>
        <target>inedii</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>are irrelevant, and that the ability to sit nearly motionless in the same position day after day, with no regard for extremes of weather including a cold winter and a monsoon season, is notable. For example, American writer George Saunders visited Palden Dorje and observed him through a single night, and was impressed by Palden Dorje's perfectly still stature, even during an evening climate that seemed unbearably cold to the much better clothed journalist.</source>
        <target>są bez znaczenia, i że zdolność siedzenia niemal bez ruchu w tej samej pozycji dzień za dniem, bez względu na ekstremalne warunki pogodowe łącznie z chłodną zimą i porą monsunową, jest godna uwagi.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>In December 2005, a nine-member government committee led by Gunjaman Lama watched Palden Dorje carefully for 48 hours and observed him not to take any food or water during that time. A video recording was also made of this test. However, they were unable to approach closer than 3 meters or take readings of his vital signs. The Nepalese government planned a more careful scientific study, but the plan was never carried out.</source>
        <target>W grudniu 2005 roku dziewięcioosobowy komitet rządowy, kierowany przez Lamę Gunjaman obserwował Paldena uważnie przez 48 godzin i zaobserwował, że nie spożywał on żadnego jedzenia ani wody w tym czasie. Nagranie wideo tego testu zostało nakręcone. Jednak nie mogli oni podejść bliżej niż 3 metry, czy też dokonać pomiaru jego czynności życiowych. Rząd nepalski planował bardziej wnikliwe badanie naukowe, ale plan ten nigdy nie został wykonany.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>In 2007, the Discovery Channel produced a documentary titled</source>
        <target>W 2007 roku Discovery Channel nakręcił film dokumentalny pod tytułem</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>The Boy With Divine Powers</source>
        <target>Chłopiec, o boskich mocach /film ten pojawił się 6 czerwca w TVP2 pod tytułem „Młody Budda”</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On their first, four-day attempt, the film crew was required to stay outside a guarded barbed-wire fence, and their camera's infrared capabilities did not pick up evidence of a body at the base of the tree where Palden Dorje sat during their non-stop recording. On a second attempt a few weeks later, however, the film crew was able to film Palden Dorje continuously for 96 hours, day and night, during which time he did not drink any fluids or eat any food. According to scientists on the documentary, an average person would be expected to die from kidney failure after four days without drinking any fluids. The boy showed no signs of classical physical deterioration caused by dehydration. A close inspection by the film crew of the area around the tree where Palden Dorje was sitting revealed no hidden food supply or water pipes.</source>
        <target>Podczas ich pierwszej, czterodniowej próby, od ekipy filmowej wymagano, by została ona poza strzeżonym ogrodzeniem z druta kolczastego, i możliwości podczerwone ich kamery nie zebrały dowodu obecności człowieka u podstaw drzewa, gdzie Palden Dorje siedział podczas ich nieprzerywanego nagrywania. Podczas drugiej próby, jednak, ekipa filmowa była w stanie filmować Paldena Dorje stale przez 96 godzin, dzień i noc, podczas których nie pił żadnych napojów, ani też nie spożywał żadnej żywności. Według naukowców wypowiadających się w tym filmie dokumentalnym, od przeciętnej osoby spodziewanoby się zgonu z powodu niewydolności nerek po czterech dniach bez picia jakichkolwiek cieczy. Chłopiec nie dawał żadnych oznak klasycznego pogorszenia stanu fizycznego spowodowanego odwodnieniem. Dokładna inspekcja okolicy naokoło drzewa, gdzie siedział Palden Dorje dokonana przez ekipę filmową nie odkryła żadnych skrytych dostaw żywności, czy kanałów wodnych.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 10 November 2008, Palden Dorje</source>
        <target>10 Listopada 2008 roku Palden Dorje</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>reappeared and spoke</source>
        <target>wystąpił na nowo i przemówił</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>to a group of devotees in the remote jungle of Ratanpuri, 150 km (95 miles) southeast of Kathmandu, near Nijgadh. His hair was shoulder-length and his body was wrapped in a white cloth.</source>
        <target>do grupy oddanych w oddalonej dżungli Ratanpuri, 150 km (95 mil) na południowy wschód od Katmandu, niedaleko Nijgadh. Włosy jego sięgały ramion, a ciało owinięte było białym płótnem.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>His devotees believe he attained enlightenment at Bodh Gaya in Bihar, which borders Nepal – the place where Siddartha Gautama attained enlightenment.</source>
        <target>Jego wielbiciele wierzą, iż osiągnął oświecenie w Bodh Gaya w Bihar, graniczącym z Nepalem - miejscu, gdzie Siddartha Gautama osiągnął oświecenie.</target>
      </trans-unit>

    </body>
  </file>
</xliff>