<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<xliff version="1.0">
  <file original="global" source-language="en" datatype="plaintext">
    <body>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Dharma Sangha - Translation Fundraising - eTapasvi.com</source>
        <target>Дхарма Сангха - Cредства для перевода - eTapasvi.com</target>
      </trans-unit>     

     <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Purpose</source>
        <target>Цель</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>LTJ/Andrea Good's job description as a translator and coordinator of the Bodhi Sravan Dharma Sangha Committee:</source>
        <target>Описание обязанностей Андреа Гуд (LTJ) как переводчицы и координатора Комитета Бодхи Сраван Дхарма Сангха:</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Translating Dharma Sangha's prayers, chants and Dharma and preparing other texts including audio and visual materials for Dharma Sangha's teaching next year.</source>
        <target>Перевод молитв Дхарма Сангхи, песнопений и Дхармы, а также подготовка других текстов и аудио-видео материалов для учения Дхарма Сангхи в следующем году.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Writing a second book similar "Reflections on Palden Dorje" with greater accuracy and more emphasis on his life story.</source>
        <target>Написание второй книги наподобие "Размышления о Палдене Дордже", но с большим вниманием к деталям и большим упором на историю его жизни.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Overseeing the completion of Terthup (receipts, ideas etc.)</source>
        <target>Контроль за строительством Тертхупа (слежение за денежными поступлениями, идеи, предложения и т.д.)</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Completing the children's picture book.</source>
        <target>Завершение работы над книгой иллюстраций для детей.</target>
      </trans-unit>      

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Working second to Khenpo Sonam Gyurme on the advisory team which will include the development of the site as a jungle meditational sanctuary and the academy for those wishing to learn meditation. This will include a library and exhibition hall for Dharma Sangha's materials and Thangkas.</source>
        <target>Работа вместе с Кхенпо Сонамом Гьюрме в команде консультантов, которая будет включать в себя создание места для медитации в джунглях и академии для желающих научиться медитации. В ней будет располагаться библиотека и выставочный зал для различных материалов, тханк (икон) Дхармы Сангхи.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Directing internet news from the site.</source>
        <target>Распространение через Интернет новостей с места событий.</target>
      </trans-unit>      

     <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Continuing to receive photos, names and further blessing requests which Dharma Sangha will see and bless.</source>
        <target>Продолжать получать фото, имена и прочие материалы, которые будут передаваться Дхарма Сангхе для благословления.</target>
      </trans-unit>

     <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Details</source>
        <target>Детали</target>
      </trans-unit>

     <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>"At present my goal is to pay off my last ticket of $1200 and buy a new one for approximately the same. (Had I continued work in Japan, I would have paid off the first ticket through my job, but the committee would like me back as soon as possible.)</source>
        <target>"В настоящее время я пытаюсь вернуть долг за билет стоимостью в $1200 и купить новый примерно в ту же цену. (Если бы я продолжала работать в Японии, я бы заработала на первый билет, но комитет хочет, чтобы я вернулась как можно скорее)</target>
      </trans-unit>

     <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>I would appreciate at least $3600 for food and living expenses for the next three months for my son in Japan and myself in Nepal.  The total is as follows:"</source>
        <target>Я планирую накопить, по крайней мере, еще $3600 для питания и проживания в течение следующих трёх месяцев моего сына в Японии и для меня в Непале. Ниже приведены детали:"</target>
      </trans-unit>     
  
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>-Andrea Good</source>
        <target>-Андреа Гуд</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Tickets</source>
        <target>Билеты</target>
      </trans-unit>      

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>From Sapporo (New Chitose) via Seoul (Incheon) Korean Airlines to Kathmandu (Tribhuvan)(1200 x 2)</source>
        <target>Перелёт из Саппоро (Нью-Титосэ) через Сеул (Инчхон) корейской авиакомпанией в Катманду (Трибхуван) (1200х2)</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Living</source>
        <target>Проживание</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>$800 for rent and utilities, $400 for food (x 3 months)</source>
        <target>$800 за аренду и коммунальные услуги, $400 для питания (х 3 месяца)</target>
      </trans-unit>      

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Total</source>
        <target>Итого</target>
      </trans-unit>      

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Donate</source>
        <target>Пожертвовать</target>
      </trans-unit>

<!-- утф -->
    </body>
  </file>
</xliff>