<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<xliff version="1.0">
  <file original="global" source-language="en" datatype="plaintext">
    <body>

<!--questions -->

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Where is Dharma Sangha now?</source>
        <target>Ou se trouve Dharma Sangha en ce moment ?</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Is Dharma Sangha still not eating anything or just eating herbs from the jungle?</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>      
  
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Why is he meditating? What does he want to achieve?</source>
        <target>Pourquoi médite-t-il ? Que veut-il atteindre ?</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Is Dharma Sangha already enlightened?</source>
        <target>Dharma Sangha a-t-il déjà atteint l'illumination ?</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Has he already become a Buddha?</source>
        <target>Est-il déjà devenu un Bouddha ?</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Is his teaching based on Buddhism or any other religions like Hinduism?</source>
        <target>Son enseignement est-il basé sur le Bouddhisme ou sur d'autres religions comme l'Hindouisme ?</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>What does "Bodhi Shravan Dharma Sangha" mean?</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>How can I receive blessing from Dharma Sangha?</source>
        <target>Comment puis-je recevoir une bénédiction de Dharma Sangha ?</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>How to reach Ratanpur and Terthup?</source>
        <target>Comment se rendre à Ratanpur ou Terthup ?</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>What does Jyampa, Ginphen, Maitri, Maitreya and Metta mean?</source>
        <target>Que signifie Jyampa, Ginphen, Maitri, Maitreya et Metta ?</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>I am going to Halkhoriya Jungle. What should I take with me? I also would like to bring some gifts, what is the best choice?</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
  
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>How can I get to Halkhoriya Jungle?</source>
        <target>Comment se rendre à la jungle d'Halkhoriya ?</target>
      </trans-unit>


<!--answers-->

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He is meditating in Halkhoriya Jungle, Nepal's Bara District.</source>
        <target>Il médite dans la jungle d'Halkhoriya, dans le district Népalais de Bara.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He is not eating anything.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Dharma Sangha wants to liberate the whole world by spreading Dharma and insight he’ve gained through his meditation.</source>
        <target>Dharma Sangha veut libérer le monde entier en répendant le Dharma et la perception intérieur qu'il a acquit par la méditation.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Yes, he is already enlightened. The first stages of enlightenment occurred in his room at home.</source>
        <target>Oui, il a déjà atteint l'illumination. Le premier stade d'illumination est survenu dans sa chambre à son domicile.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Dharma Sangha can’t tell it now. Time will reveal.</source>
        <target>Dharma Sangha ne peut le dire maintenant. Cela se fera avec le temps.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>It is actually called Bodhi Shravan Dharma Sangha, but it includes all religions, no one is excluded. Dharma Sangha will be moving forward by including all existing religions of the world.</source>
        <target>Cela se nomme Bodhi Shravan Dharma Sangha, mais cela inclut toutes les religions, aucune n'est exlue. Dharma Sangua souhaite inclure prochainement toutes les religions du monde existant à ce jour.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Bodhi: enlightenment, awakened.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Shravan: attending to, heeding, listening.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Dharma: wisdom.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Sangha: association, assembly, community.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Thus "Bodhi Shravan Dharma Sangha" is the wisdom as heeded from enlightened ones.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Please go to</source>
        <target>Veuillez vous rendre à</target>
      </trans-unit>
           
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Impractical gifts are not really good to bring (pictures, vases etc). Dharma Sangha does not accept gifts. Below is a list of small practical things, which are needed regularly in the jungle:</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Scissors.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Kitchenware (bigger pots, which bear direct fire, cutting knives, any non-electric kitchen tools, as there is not much electricity on the site, bigger plastic buckets and storing boxes to keep food safe from monkey-robbers, etc.)</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Pens and copybooks.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>CANDLES (not perfumed ones).</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Sleeping bag or blankets.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>    
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Flashlights (solar powered, if possible).</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Sealed medicine with English leaflets (especially for colds, cough, wound disinfectants, bandages and first aid supplies).</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Lighters.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>100% natural material clothes or mats for sitting on the ground.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>If anyone has a notebook or laptop, which he or she does not need, and which has a long-lasting battery, it would be also appreciated by the young monks, who are helping Khenpo to write and translate the texts of Dharma Sangha prayers and teachings, etc.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Soap, shampoo, laundry soap.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Mosquito nets and natural sprays.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
--> 
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>The most convenience place for foreigner is to land in Kathmandu. From Kathmandu it is about 6 hours drive to Parsa Bridge if you can take a bus or a private vehicle. From Parsa Bridge to Halkhoriya Jungle (about 6-7 km) you can take a tractor, which belongs to Bodhi Shrawan Dharma Sangha, or a 4-wheel vehicle to reach there. The road is a dry river bed and it is rough and bumpy ride.</source>
        <target>Le plus pratique pour les étrangers est d'atterrir à Katmandu. De Katmandu il y a 6 heures de route jusqu'au pont de Parsa, si vous pouvez prendre un bus ou un véhicule privé. Du pont de Parsa jusqu'à la jungle de Halkhoriya (environ 6-7 km) vous pouvez prendre un tracteur appartenant au Bodhi Shrawan Dharma Sangha, ou un 4x4. La route est un lit de rivière à sec difficile et cahoteuse.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Gompa, Ratanpur</source>
        <target>Gompa, Ratanpur</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Jyampa, Ginphen, Maitri, Maitreya and Metta mean "loving kindness".</source>
        <target>Jyampa, Ginphen, Maitri, Maitreya et Metta signifie "amour bienveillant".</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
<!-- утф -->
    </body>
  </file>
</xliff>