<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<xliff version="1.0">
  <file original="global" source-language="en" datatype="plaintext">
    <body>

<!--questions -->
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Where is Dharma Sangha now?</source>
        <target>Dove si trova adesso Dharma Sangha?</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Is Dharma Sangha still not eating anything or just eating herbs from the jungle?</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
  
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Why is he meditating? What does he want to achieve?</source>
        <target>Perché medita? Qual è il Suo scopo?</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Is Dharma Sangha already enlightened?</source>
        <target>Dharma Sangha è già illuminato?</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Has he already become a Buddha?</source>
        <target>È già diventato un Budda?</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Is his teaching based on Buddhism or any other religions like Hinduism?</source>
        <target>I Suoi insegnamenti si basano sul Buddismo o su un'altra religione come ad esempio l'Induismo?</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>What does "Bodhi Shravan Dharma Sangha" mean?</source>
        <target>Cosa significa “Bodhi Shravan Dharma Sangha”?</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>How can I receive blessing from Dharma Sangha?</source>
        <target>Come posso avere una benedizione di Dharma Sangha?</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>How to reach Ratanpur and Terthup?</source>
        <target>Come arrivare a Ratanpuri e a Terthup</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>What does Jyampa, Ginphen, Maitri, Maitreya and Metta mean?</source>
        <target>Che cosa vogliono dire le parole Jyampa, Ginphen, maitrī, Maitreya e mettā ?</target>
      </trans-unit>
            

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>I am going to Halkhoriya Jungle. What should I take with me? I also would like to bring some gifts, what is the best choice?</source>
        <target>Ho intenzione di andare nella Giungla di Halkhoriya. Cosa dovrei avere con me? Vorrei inoltre portare dei doni. Quali sono gli oggetti migliori?</target>
      </trans-unit>
  
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>How can I get to Halkhoriya Jungle?</source>
        <target>Come posso raggiungere la giungla di Halkhoriya</target>
      </trans-unit>


<!--answers-->

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He is meditating in Halkhoriya Jungle, Bara District in Nepal.</source>
        <target>Si trova nella giungla di Halkhoriya, in Nepal, e medita e detta i Suoi insegnamenti a Khenpo.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He is not eating anything.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Dharma Sangha wants to liberate the whole world by spreading Dharma and insight he’ve gained through his meditation.</source>
        <target>Dharma Sangha intende liberare il mondo intero diffondendo il Dharma (Rettitudine) e gli insegnamenti che ha ottenuto nel corso delle Sue meditazioni.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Yes, he is already enlightened. The first stages of enlightenment occurred in his room at home.</source>
        <target>Sì, è già illuminato.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Dharma Sangha can’t tell it now. Time will reveal.</source>
        <target>Dharma Sangha al momento non è in grado di dirlo. Sarà il tempo a farlo.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>It is actually called Bodhi Shravan Dharma Sangha, but it includes all religions, no one is excluded. Dharma Sangha will be moving forward by including all existing religions of the world.</source>
        <target>Di fatto è chiamato Bodhi Shravan Dharma Sangha, ma include tutte le religioni, nessuna esclusa. Dharma Sangha si spingerà oltre includendo tutte le religioni esistenti nel mondo.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Bodhi: enlightenment, awakened.</source>
        <target>Bodhi: illuminazione, risvegli(at)o.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Shravan: attending to, heeding, listening.</source>
        <target>Shravan: (śravaṇa) prestare attenzione, dare retta, ascoltare</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Dharma: wisdom.</source>
        <target>Dharma: saggezza.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Sangha: association, assembly, community.</source>
        <target>Sangha: associazione, assemblea, comunità.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Thus "Bodhi Shravan Dharma Sangha" is the wisdom as heeded from enlightened ones.</source>
        <target>"Bodhi Shravan Dharma Sangha", quindi, è la saggezza come viene percepita dai risvegliati.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Please go to</source>
        <target>Vai a</target>
      </trans-unit>

     
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Impractical gifts are not really good to bring (pictures, vases, etc). Below is a list of small practical things, which are needed regularly in the jungle:</source>
        <target>È meglio non regalare oggetti poco pratici (immaginette, vasi, ecc.). Qui di seguito vengono riportate piccole, ma utilissime cose che nella giungla fanno sempre comodo:</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Scissors.</source>
        <target>Forbici.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Plastic buckets and boxes for storing food to keep it safe from monkey-robbers, etc.</source>
        <target>Secchi e recipienti di plastica per la conservazione degli alimenti che saranno così al sicuro dalle scimmie (e non solo).</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Pens and copybooks.</source>
        <target>Penne, matite e quaderni.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>CANDLES (not perfumed ones).</source>
        <target>CANDELE (ma non quelle profumate).</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Sleeping bag, blankets, mat/mattress.</source>
        <target>Sacco a pelo, lenzuola, materassino.</target>
      </trans-unit>   
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Flashlights (solar powered, if possible).</source>
        <target>Torce (possibilmente a energia solare).</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Sealed medicine with English leaflets (especially for colds, cough, wound disinfectants, bandages and first aid supplies).</source>
        <target>Farmaci in scatole chiuse con foglietti illustrativi in inglese (in particolare per raffreddore e tosse), disinfettanti, bende e kit di pronto soccorso.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Lighters.</source>
        <target>Accendisigari.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>100% natural material clothes or mats for sitting on the ground.</source>
        <target>Abiti in tessuto 100% naturale o cuscini per sedersi a terra.</target>
      </trans-unit>      
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Soap, shampoo, laundry soap.</source>
        <target>Sapone da bagno, shampoo, sapone di Marsiglia o altro.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Mosquito nets and natural sprays.</source>
        <target>Zanzariere e spray naturali.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Make sure that Dharma Sangha will accept visitors on the day you are going to the jungle (every Tuesday and Saturday from 11 am to 1 pm for now) by checking updates on website and forum</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Keep in mind that it is not allowed to stay in Halkhoriya overnight and it is not advised to walk in jungle after 5pm, because wild animals are very active in the evening. So you should plan to reach in the jungle early in the morning and leave before 5 pm.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Come to Kathmandu (if you are not coming from India, or Bhutan, or China.)</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Make arrangements with Committee (contact details will be available later).</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>From Kathmandu you can take a jeep "Tata Sumo" (name of popular jeep in the area) in Bolkhu place. The journey by the jeep is a 4-hour drive from Kathmandu to Simara. The other alternative is travelling by bus up to Simara which is 10-11 hour drive at night.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>From Simara you should get to Pilua Junction or Pasaha Bridge (Pilua village bus stop). You can take the 20 minute bus ride or take a "Tata Sumo"  (contact Lama Hotel, owned by Krishna meme, pronounced meh-meh meaning “respected grandfather”, though one need not be as old as a grandfather to earn this title).</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>From Pasaha Bridge to Halkhoriya Jungle (about 6-7 km) you can take a tractor which belongs to Committee. The road is a dry river bed and it is rough and bumpy ride.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Gompa, Ratanpur</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Jyampa, Ginphen, Maitri, Maitreya and Metta mean "loving kindness".</source>
        <target>Le parole Jyampa, Ginphen, maitrī, Maitreya e mettā vogliono dire “amorevole benevolenza”.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
    </body>
  </file>
</xliff>