<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<xliff version="1.0">
  <file original="global" source-language="en" datatype="plaintext">
    <body>

<!--questions -->
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Where is Dharma Sangha now?</source>
        <target>Dove si trova adesso Dharma Sangha?</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Is Dharma Sangha still not eating anything or just eating herbs from the jungle?</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
  
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Why is he meditating? What does he want to achieve?</source>
        <target>Perché medita? Qual è il Suo scopo?</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Is Dharma Sangha already enlightened?</source>
        <target>Dharma Sangha è già illuminato?</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Has he already become a Buddha?</source>
        <target>È già diventato un Budda?</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Is his teaching based on Buddhism or any other religions like Hinduism?</source>
        <target>I Suoi insegnamenti si basano sul Buddismo o su un'altra religione come ad esempio l'Induismo?</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>What does "Bodhi Shravan Dharma Sangha" mean?</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>How can I receive blessing from Dharma Sangha?</source>
        <target>Come posso avere una benedizione di Dharma Sangha?</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>How to reach Ratanpur and Terthup?</source>
        <target>Come arrivare a Ratanpuri e a Terthup</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>What does Jyampa, Ginphen, Maitri, Maitreya and Metta mean?</source>
        <target>Che cosa vogliono dire le parole Jyampa, Ginphen, maitrī, Maitreya e mettā ?</target>
      </trans-unit>
            

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>I am going to Halkhoriya Jungle. What should I take with me? I also would like to bring some gifts, what is the best choice?</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
  
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>How can I get to Halkhoriya Jungle?</source>
        <target>Come posso raggiungere la giungla di Halkhoriya</target>
      </trans-unit>


<!--answers-->

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He is meditating in Halkhoriya Jungle, Nepal's Bara District.</source>
        <target>Si trova nella giungla di Halkhoriya, in Nepal, e medita e detta i Suoi insegnamenti a Khenpo.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He is not eating anything.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Dharma Sangha wants to liberate the whole world by spreading Dharma and insight he’ve gained through his meditation.</source>
        <target>Dharma Sangha intende liberare il mondo intero diffondendo il Dharma (Rettitudine) e gli insegnamenti che ha ottenuto nel corso delle Sue meditazioni.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Yes, he is already enlightened. The first stages of enlightenment occurred in his room at home.</source>
        <target>Sì, è già illuminato.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Dharma Sangha can’t tell it now. Time will reveal.</source>
        <target>Dharma Sangha al momento non è in grado di dirlo. Sarà il tempo a farlo.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>It is actually called Bodhi Shravan Dharma Sangha, but it includes all religions, no one is excluded. Dharma Sangha will be moving forward by including all existing religions of the world.</source>
        <target>Di fatto è chiamato Bodhi Shravan Dharma Sangha, ma include tutte le religioni, nessuna esclusa. Dharma Sangha si spingerà oltre includendo tutte le religioni esistenti nel mondo.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Bodhi: enlightenment, awakened.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Shravan: attending to, heeding, listening.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Dharma: wisdom.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Sangha: association, assembly, community.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Thus "Bodhi Shravan Dharma Sangha" is the wisdom as heeded from enlightened ones.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Please go to</source>
        <target>Vai a</target>
      </trans-unit>

     
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Impractical gifts are not really good to bring (pictures, vases etc). Dharma Sangha does not accept gifts. Below is a list of small practical things, which are needed regularly in the jungle:</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Scissors.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Kitchenware (bigger pots, which bear direct fire, cutting knives, any non-electric kitchen tools, as there is not much electricity on the site, bigger plastic buckets and storing boxes to keep food safe from monkey-robbers, etc.)</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Pens and copybooks.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>CANDLES (not perfumed ones).</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Sleeping bag or blankets.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>   
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Flashlights (solar powered, if possible).</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Sealed medicine with English leaflets (especially for colds, cough, wound disinfectants, bandages and first aid supplies).</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Lighters.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>100% natural material clothes or mats for sitting on the ground.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>If anyone has a notebook or laptop, which he or she does not need, and which has a long-lasting battery, it would be also appreciated by the young monks, who are helping Khenpo to write and translate the texts of Dharma Sangha prayers and teachings, etc.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Soap, shampoo, laundry soap.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Mosquito nets and natural sprays.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>
     
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>The most convenience place for foreigner is to land in Kathmandu. From Kathmandu it is about 6 hours drive to Parsa Bridge if you can take a bus or a private vehicle. From Parsa Bridge to Halkhoriya Jungle (about 6-7 km) you can take a tractor, which belongs to Bodhi Shrawan Dharma Sangha, or a 4-wheel vehicle to reach there. The road is a dry river bed and it is rough and bumpy ride.</source>
        <target>Per gli stranieri, la via più semplice è quella di atterrare a Kathnmandu; dalla capitale ci vogliono circa 6 ore di guida per arrivare a Parsa Bridge (con l’autobus o un veicolo privato). Da Parsa Bridge alla giungla di Halkhoriya (6-7 km circa), si può prendere un trattore, di Bodhi Shrawan Dharma Sangha, o un veicolo 4x4. La strada è il letto di un fiume in secca ed è accidentata e sassosa.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Gompa, Ratanpur</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Jyampa, Ginphen, Maitri, Maitreya and Metta mean "loving kindness".</source>
        <target>Le parole Jyampa, Ginphen, maitrī, Maitreya e mettā vogliono dire “amorevole benevolenza”.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
    </body>
  </file>
</xliff>