<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<xliff version="1.0">
  <file original="global" source-language="en" datatype="plaintext">
    <body>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Dharma Sangha - Translation Fundraising - eTapasvi.com</source>
        <target>Dharma Sangha - Zbieranie funduszy na tłumaczenie - eTapasvi.com</target>
      </trans-unit>     

     <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Purpose</source>
        <target>Cel</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>LTJ/Andrea Good's job description as a translator and coordinator of the Bodhi Sravan Dharma Sangha Committee:</source>
        <target>Opis pracy LTJ/Andrei Good jako tłumacza i koordynatora Komitetu Bodhi Sravan Dharma Sangha: </target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Translating Dharma Sangha's prayers, chants and Dharma and preparing other texts including audio and visual materials for Dharma Sangha's teaching next year.</source>
        <target>Tłumaczenie modlitw, pieśni i Dharmy Dharma Sanghi, i przygotowywanie innych tekstów, w tym materiałów audiowizualnych do nauczania Dharma Sanghi w przyszłym roku.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Writing a second book similar "Reflections on Palden Dorje" with greater accuracy and more emphasis on his life story.</source>
        <target>Pisanie drugiej książki podobnej do "Refleksji nad Paldenem Dorje" z większą dokładnością i większym podkreśleniem jego historii życiowej.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Overseeing the completion of Terthup (receipts, ideas etc.)</source>
        <target>Nadzorowanie ukończenia Terthupu (rachunki, pomysły etc.)</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Completing the children's picture book.</source>
        <target>Dokończenie obrazkowej książki dla dzieci.</target>
      </trans-unit>      

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Working second to Khenpo Sonam Gyurme on the advisory team which will include the development of the site as a jungle meditational sanctuary and the academy for those wishing to learn meditation. This will include a library and exhibition hall for Dharma Sangha's materials and Thangkas.</source>
        <target>Pracowanie zaraz obok Khenpo Sonam Gyurme przy ekipie doradczej, co będzie obejmować rozwinięcie miejsca jako medytacyjnego sanktuarium dżungli i akademii dla tych, którzy pragną nauczyć się medytacji. Będzie to obejmować bibliotekę i hall wystawowy na materiały Dharma Sanghi i Thangki.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Directing internet news from the site.</source>
        <target>Kierowanie wiadomości internetowych z miejsca.</target>
      </trans-unit>      

     <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Continuing to receive photos, names and further blessing requests which Dharma Sangha will see and bless.</source>
        <target>Kontynuacja otrzymywania zdjęć, nazwisk i dalszych próśb o pobłogosławienie, które Dharma Sangha zobaczy i pobłogosławi.</target>
      </trans-unit>

     <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Details</source>
        <target>Szczegóły</target>
      </trans-unit>

     <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>"At present my goal is to pay off my last ticket of $1200 and buy a new one for approximately the same. (Had I continued work in Japan, I would have paid off the first ticket through my job, but the committee would like me back as soon as possible.)</source>
        <target>"W tym momencie mym teraźniejszym celem jest spłacenie mojego ostatniego biletu w cenie $1200 i kupienie nowego za tę samą sumę w przybliżeniu. (Gdybym pracowała dalej w Japonii, spłaciłabym pierwszy bilet dzęki mojej pracy, ale komitet chciałby mnie mieć z powrotem jak najwcześniej)</target>
      </trans-unit>

     <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>I would appreciate at least $3600 for food and living expenses for the next three months for my son in Japan and myself in Nepal.  The total is as follows:"</source>
        <target>Byłabym wdzięczna za conajmniej $3600 na wyżywienie i wydatki życiowe na kolejne 3 miesiące dla mego syna w Japonii i dla mnie w Nepalu. Całość wygląda następująco:"</target>
      </trans-unit>     
  
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>-Andrea Good</source>
        <target>-Andrea Good</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Tickets</source>
        <target>Bilety</target>
      </trans-unit>      

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>From Sapporo (New Chitose) via Seoul (Incheon) Korean Airlines to Kathmandu (Tribhuvan)(1200 x 2)</source>
        <target>Z Sapporo (New Chitose) przez Seoul (Incheon) Korean Airlines do Kathmandu (Tribhuvan)(1200 x 2)</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Living</source>
        <target>Utrzymanie</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>$800 for rent and utilities, $400 for food (x 3 months)</source>
        <target>$800 za wynajem i opłaty za użytkowanie, $400 na żywność (x 3 months)</target>
      </trans-unit>      

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Total</source>
        <target>Suma</target>
      </trans-unit>      

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Donate</source>
        <target>Datek</target>
      </trans-unit>

    </body>
  </file>
</xliff>