<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<xliff version="1.0">
  <file original="global" source-language="en" datatype="plaintext">
    <body>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Dharma Sangha - Translation Fundraising - eTapasvi.com</source>
        <target>Dharma Sangha - Recaudaciуn de Fondos - eTapasvi.com</target>
      </trans-unit>     

     <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Purpose</source>
        <target>Objetivo</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>LTJ/Andrea Good's job description as a translator and coordinator of the Bodhi Sravan Dharma Sangha Committee:</source>
        <target>La descripción de LTJ/Andrea Good como traductora y coordinadora del Comité Bodhi Sravan Dharma Sangha: </target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Translating Dharma Sangha's prayers, chants and Dharma and preparing other texts including audio and visual materials for Dharma Sangha's teaching next year.</source>
        <target>Traducir las oraciones, cantos y Dharma de Guru Dharma Sangha y preparar otros textos incluyendo materiales de audio y video para las enseñanzas de Guru Dharma Sangha para el próximo año.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Writing a second book similar "Reflections on Palden Dorje" with greater accuracy and more emphasis on his life story.</source>
        <target>Escribir un segundo libro similar "Reflexiones sobre Palden Dorje" con mayor precisión y más enfasis en la historia de su vida.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Overseeing the completion of Terthup (receipts, ideas etc.)</source>
        <target>Supervisar la realizaciуn de Terhup (recibos, ideas, etc.)</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Completing the children's picture book.</source>
        <target>Completar el libro de fotos de niños.</target>
      </trans-unit>      

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Working second to Khenpo Sonam Gyurme on the advisory team which will include the development of the site as a jungle meditational sanctuary and the academy for those wishing to learn meditation. This will include a library and exhibition hall for Dharma Sangha's materials and Thangkas.</source>
        <target>Trabajar segunda despus de Khenpo Sonam Gyurme en el equipo de asesoría, el cual incluiré el desarrollo del lugar como una selva santuario de meditación para aquellos que deseen aprender meditación. Esto incluiré una biblioteca y una sala de exhibición para los materiales de Dharma Sangha y Thangkas.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Directing internet news from the site.</source>
        <target>Dirigir las noticias por internet desde la página web</target>
      </trans-unit>      

     <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Continuing to receive photos, names and further blessing requests which Dharma Sangha will see and bless.</source>
        <target>Continuar recibiendo fotos, nombres y más solicitudes de bendiciones las cuales Dharma Sangha verá y bendecirá.</target>
      </trans-unit>

     <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Details</source>
        <target>Detalles</target>
      </trans-unit>

     <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>"At present my goal is to pay off my last ticket of $1200 and buy a new one for approximately the same. (Had I continued work in Japan, I would have paid off the first ticket through my job, but the committee would like me back as soon as possible.)</source>
        <target>"Ahora my meta es pagar mi último pasaje de avión de $1200 y comprar uno nuevo por aproximadamente lo mismo. (Si hubiese seguido trabajando en Japón, hubiese podido pagar my primer pasaje con mi trabajo pero el comité quiere que regrese lo más pronto posible.)</target>
      </trans-unit>

     <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>I would appreciate at least $3600 for food and living expenses for the next three months for my son in Japan and myself in Nepal.  The total is as follows:"</source>
        <target>Yo les agradecería enviarme al menos $3600 para comida y viáticos para los próximos tres meses para mi hijo en Japón y para mi en Nepal. El total es el siguiento: "</target>
      </trans-unit>     
  
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>-Andrea Good</source>
        <target>Andrea Good</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Tickets</source>
        <target>Pasajes de avión</target>
      </trans-unit>      

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>From Sapporo (New Chitose) via Seoul (Incheon) Korean Airlines to Kathmandu (Tribhuvan)(1200 x 2)</source>
        <target>Desde Sapporo (Nuevo Chitose) via Seúl (Incheon) Aerolineas Koreanas a Kathmandu (Tribhuvan) (1200 x 2)</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Living</source>
        <target>Viáticos</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>$800 for rent and utilities, $400 for food (x 3 months)</source>
        <target>$800 para la renta y servicios, $400 para comida (x 3 meses)</target>
      </trans-unit>      

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Total</source>
        <target>Total</target>
      </trans-unit>      

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Donate</source>
        <target>Donar</target>
      </trans-unit>

    </body>
  </file>
</xliff>